视频资料来自网络 版权归BBC所有
听写:alanalg/糖衣楷书/jinmy99/Natas/Geofflyk/清野
仅供学习交流使用 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译:小小c/Natas/Hopsen/糖衣楷书/Geofflyk/Oliver/清野
水平有限 难免有误 敬请谅解
时间轴/校对:胖子/顿顿/清野过客
新浪微博关注 TopGear字幕组
特效:最沉重的负担
新浪微博关注TopGear字幕组
压制:清野过客
TopGear字幕组
完美公路之旅2
去年 理查德哈蒙德和我从威尼斯出发
Last year, Richard Hammond and I set off from Venice
进行了一场所谓的完美公路之旅
on what should have been, the Perfect Road Trip.
我们总能在正确的道路上驾驶合适的车
We always had the right car for the right road.
好一台机器
What a machine!
我们想要阳光 就出太阳
The sun shone when we wanted it to...
快看啊
Look at this now!
不想要时 就会下雨
and the rain came when we didn't.
一切都很棒
It was brilliant...
直到某个时刻
right up to the moment
法国佬没收了我们的驾照
when the French constabulary took away our driving licenses.
哦 好吧
Oh. Right.
所以今年 我们吸取教训
So this year, with the lesson learned,
我们决定再进行一次完美公路之旅
we thought we do the perfect road trip, again.
而这次 我们不会再出错
And this time, we'd get it right.
请别换台
Do not adjust your set.
我知道去年就是这么开场的
驾驶一艘Riva Aquarama
I know this is how it began last year, on a Riva Aquarama,
世界上最棒的快艇
the world's best speed boat,
在威尼斯 建造于海上的最棒城市
in Venice,the world's best city that's built on the sea.
没错 但你去年的所见所闻
Yeah. But there are some major differences
将和今年有诸多不同
between what you saw last year and what you'll see this time.
-首先 他更胖了 -是哒没错
Firstly, he's even fatter. Oh, I have. He is.
其次 我们彻底改变了线路
And secondly we have completely change the route.
哦对 今年我们不去法国 因为说实话
Oh yeah. This year we are not going to France because frankly they are,
他们是一群傻..
well they are bunch of f…
相反 我们会留在意大利 上帝的私人赛车场
Instead, we shall be staying in Italy, God's personal race track,
从威尼斯出发 途径托斯卡纳和罗马
going from Venice down through Tuscany and Rome
还有超凡的阿马尔菲海岸
and along the spectacular Amalfi Coast.
我们驾驶的车辆甚至比去年更棒
And the cars we'll be using will be even better than they were last year.
更快 更强 更吵
Faster. Harder. Louder.
我们甚至把终点安排在卡普里岛上
We'd even arranged to finish on the glittering jet set island of Capri,
驾驶的正是经典的福特卡普里
in a couple of classic Ford Capris.
这次一定完美
Nothing could go wrong this time.
事实上 我们今年选定的道路遵照圣经
Frankly, the roads that we've lined up this year are biblical…
也不是
well they're not biblical,
它们更现代 但是一样的壮观
they are more modern than that,but they are magnificent.
而我们驾驶的车辆..
And the cars we have to drive on them…
所以我们策划了一大堆激动人心的桥段
So there's a whole exciting thrilling bag of things we've got lined up,
但我们没加进去的是
but one thing we haven't put in it…
詹姆斯梅 他没有参加
is James May. James May is not here.
这一点才显得更完美
Which is what really makes it perfect.
没有龟速船长 我们才能体验意大利应有的速度
You lose Captain Slow, we can go with the sort of speeds they like in Italy.
我还有件事 今年准备的特别惊喜
And I have one extra thing,one extra little piece of perfection this year…
-又来了 -在我的完美之旅中
-Now, here we go.  –in my perfect road trip.
不是批评 我们在国外 但这是头一次
No critical, for the first time ever, food,we're abroad,
一般我得靠薯片维生
ordinarily,I prety much starve or survive on crisps.
史上第一次 这次我不只要吃外国菜
This time, for the first time, not only am I going to be able to eat foreign food,
还会爱上它 因为我们要去博洛尼亚
I'm gonna love it because we are going to Bologna,
肉酱意大利面的故乡 全世界我最爱的食物
home of spaghetti bolognaise,my favorite food in the world.
博洛尼亚 我会像当地人一样爱吃它
Bologna, Bolognese, I'll be able to eat like a local and love it.
很快 我们靠岸了
Soon, we docked the boat and we're ready to
准备见识旅途中所用的第一辆车
meet the cars we've chosen for the first leg of the journey.
理查德将驾驶全新的5.2升V10兰博基尼Huracan
Richard would be using the brand new 5.2 liter V10 Lamborghini Huracan,
期待已久的盖拉多换代版
the long awaited replacement for the Gallardo.
而我会开这台 同样新的迈凯伦650S
And I'd be using this, the equally new McLaren 650S,
搭载3.8升双涡轮增压V8
which comes with a twin turbo 3.8 liter V8.
那么你也许会纳闷 为何我们都没选
Now,you'll probably sitting there wondering why neither of ushas chosen
法拉利458 问得好 因为它绝对是一部超凡好车
to use a Ferrari 458,and that's a good question because it is a magnificent car.
没错 但有一个致命缺陷
It is, but it has one massive flaw.
-詹姆斯梅有一辆 -没错
James May owns one. He does.
他真有 于是他完全毁了458
He does and he has completely ruined it.
现在没人想买它了
Nobody would want to buy a Ferrari 458 now.
-对 -没人了
- No.  - Nobody.
我不想开着詹姆斯梅的车到博洛尼亚
I do not want to drive to Bologna, in James May's car.
是的 就像穿着他的内裤到处跑
No, it would be like going there with his underpants.
-那会毁掉旅程的 -没错
- It would ruin the experience.  – Yes, worse.
考虑过这些 我们的前途一片光明
Whereas in these, our immediate future is bright.
我们的前途一片橘黄
Our immediate future is orange.
非常非常橘黄
Very, very orange.
耶 哈哈
Yeah haha!
好一个声浪
Yeah haha!What a noise!
詹姆斯梅纠结好久要不要买迈凯伦
James May thought long and hard about buying a McLaren,
但他考虑到它比法拉利快得多
but then he realized it was much quicker than the Ferrari so of course,
因此 身为龟速船长 他买了法拉利
being Captain Slow, he bought the Ferrari.
我之前说的是MP4-12C 那是他考虑买的
And that, was the old MP4-12C, that was what he was thinking of buying.
这台650S 这完全是另一种猛兽
This is the 650S, and this… this is a different animal.
它比12C更有侵略性
This looks more aggressive than the 12C.
部分技术源自P1
It has got some technology from the P1,
那些买了12C的人更烦恼的是 这款快得多
and much to be annoyance of those who did buy a 12C,this is a hell of a lot faster.
我右脚驾驭着641马力
I have a bit of the control of my right foot 641 break horsepower.
扭矩有500 这意味着百公里加速只要2.9秒
I have 500 torques, and all that means I can go from 0 to 60, in 2.9 seconds.
在TG赛道上12C比458快3秒
The 12C was 3 seconds faster around the Top Gear test track than the Ferrari 458,
这个 哦这个
this… oh this is…
天啊 这玩意快极了
Jesus whap that's quick.
我们有时会区别超跑和究极跑车
When we talk about supercars and the hypercars,
这就是究极跑车的速度 千真万确
this is hypercar speed,it really is.
而且 就像是12C 它出人意料的舒适
And yes,like the 12C,it's unbelievably comfortable,
就像是驾着一朵筋斗云
it is like driving around, in a cloud.
因为所有的轮子都是电控的而非连杆
Because all the wheels are connected electronically rather than with anti roll bars,
他们之间没有实际联系
there's no physical connection between them.
这就意味着一个轮子颠簸 不影响其他三个
And that means when one wheel goes over a bump, it feels it but none of the others do.
因此驾驶感是如此平顺
That's why you just glide along.
于是你能开得更快 更猛 更持久
What this means is that you can go faster and harder,for longer.
因此没过多久
Which means that pretty soon,
你得停下来 好让你的队友追上
you'll have to stop somewhere,so your colleague can catch up.
闭嘴
Shut up.
什么 我啥都没说呢
What, I haven't said anything yet.
是啊 但我知道你要说什么
Yeah, but I know what you're going to say,
你会说你的车更快 当...
you're gonna go on about how your car's faster when…
没错
It is.
你看 它能跑到325km/h
What, that'll do 202 mph.
迈凯伦能跑到333 它马力更大 扭矩更强
The McLaren will do 207. It's more powerful,it's got more torque
更轻 就算不提速度 我本来也不想
it's lighter,even discussing speed,and I wasn't going to.
我要说 我觉得你的车不怎么好看
I was gonna say, I don't think your car looks very nice.
这 呃 神马
No, er, what?
-它不怎么 -你不能说它不好看
- It doesn't…you can't say it doesn't look very nice.
看看 那些折角 那么美
Look at it,its angles and it's beautiful.
你看 我无奈的同意你
Look, I will concede, reluctantly,
它是没有初见某些兰博车型时的惊喜
it's not as visually exciting as some Lamborghinis are when they first arrive.
它本该做到
-And should be.
不管怎么想 你的车屁股还是像真空吸尘器
Deny it that the back of your car still looks like the back of a vacuum cleaner.
看着像五金架子上的
It looks like something on the shelf in the electric…
是是 我不知道 我
-It does, it does.  –It… I don't know. I…
我不是说迈凯伦有多优秀 但至少比那台要好
Listen, I'm not saying that the McLaren is perfect,but it's more perfect than that.
我要你闭嘴 因为现在很危险
I want you to stop talking now because it's a danger,
我可能会同意你一部分
I might agree with you a tiny bit.
我说嘛
-Well it is .
可我不想那样
-And I don't want to do that.
我想做的是驾驶兰博基尼
What I do want to do is drive a Lamborghini.
好吧
Right.
好吧 我承认迈凯伦是一辆非常好的车
All right, I will concede that the McLaren is a very good car.
但在现实中 这台更棒
But in the real world, this is better,
是那些眼睛看不到的部分造就了不同
it's the things you can't see that make the difference.
迈凯伦的车体是碳纤维的 坚固 轻 很棒
The tub on the McLaren is carbon fiber, very strong, very light, very good.
但你要是撞了 准备换新车吧
But you ding it, basically you gonna need a new car.
这台的车体是碳纤维和铝合金 更容易修理
The tub in this is a blend of carbon fiber and aluminum,which is easier to repair.
内饰出类拔萃 有着优秀的设计
This interior, it's superb, this is how proper thought put into it.
一切都在合适的位置上 毫无困惑
Things are where they should be, there's no confusion and what's what,
一切都配得上它的外观
just for the sake of how it looks.
现在所有电子部件都来自奥迪 也就是说都管用
And all of the electronics now come from Audi,which means they work.
有个在红灯时自动熄火的装置
There's a device which shuts down the engine at the set of traffic lights,
还有四驱
and there's 4 wheel drive.
但别以为它会安分守己
But don't think that they've made it all sensible.
哦天啊 听听这个
Oh, my God. Listen to that.
它的引擎依旧是盖拉多的5.2升V10
It's got the same 5.2 liter V10 as in the Gallardo.
但是换上了新的气缸盖和排气系统
It's got the new top end, and a new exhaust system,
一踩下油门就能感觉到变化
a point that makes itself clear as soon as you put your foot down.
耶
Yeah!
它的拨片DSG变速箱和奥迪R8相同
It's got the same flappy paddle DSG gearbox as you get in the Audi R8,
这个消息非常好 因为
which is a very good news because that's one of,
这几乎是世界上最好的变速箱
if not the best gearbox in the world. Instant!
这里还有个按钮写着anima
And I‘ve got a button here,it's the “anima” button,
就是意大利语的"动物"
that's Italian for “animal”.
我猜哈蒙德正坐在兰博基尼里面讲着动物
I bet Hammond is sitting in his Lamborghini now talking about animals,
因为他不知道anima这个词
because he doesn't know that “anima”,
在意大利语里 其实是"灵魂"
which is what the button's called,in Italian means “soul”.
它有三种模式 那么我猜代表三种动物
And there are 3 different modes so I'm guessing they're like different animals?
舒适选项应该是兔子 很快 但有些松软
The soft one is probably a hare, fast but quite fluffy,
中间这个大概是猎豹
and then you can go for the middle one that's maybe a cheetah,
最后那个凶猛的就是老虎
then the really angry one is a tiger.
我要试试老虎
I'm going tiger.
按下去 悬挂立即变硬
If you push it, it just firms up the dampers.
它不会把汽车变成大象
It doesn't turn the car into an elephant.
这和动物半毛钱关系没有 好一个傻帽
Nothing to do with animals, what a blithering idiot.
很多时候Huracan驾驶起来
There are times pushing on like this when the Huracan feels
更像是跑车而非超跑 这是种赞美
more like a sports car than a supercar and that is a compliment.
因为我的意思是 它更像是某种
Because what I'm saying is it feels more like something
你能利用并驾驭的东西 并非一头蛮牛
you can use and drive hard rather than a bored bull.
转向非常优秀
The steering is superb.
天啊 这东西真棒
God, this thing is good.
它还是兰博 还是那么激动人心
It's still a Lambo. This is still exciting.
Huracan保留了兰博的真谛
当哈蒙德为此兴奋时
With Hammond now very happy that the Huracan was behaving as a true Lamborghini should,
我们驶向意大利最不为人知的几处珍宝之一
we headed into one of Italy's least well known treasures.
博洛尼亚 拥有两家篮球俱乐部
意大利第七繁忙的机场
Bologna, home to 2 basketball clubs,the 7th busiest airport in all of Italy,
还有这个 17世纪意大利的精品建筑
and this,a magnificent piece of 17th century architecture,
我知道哈蒙德想了解更多
that I knew Hammond was dying to find out about.
好 注意了哈蒙德 这是世界上最长的柱廊之一
All right, pay attention Hammond, this is the longest portico in the world, ok?
它有4公里 从博洛尼亚这头一直到那边的教堂
It's  4 kilometers,goes all the way from this part of Bologna to a church of that part,
这样人们去教堂就不会被太阳晒到
and so people can go to church without walking in the sun.
我不关心
I'm not interested.
666对柱子 你想知道为什么选这个数字吗
666 arches, and would you like to know why they chose the number of beast?
不 我只想知道哪能找到我的意大利肉酱面
No, what I'd like to know is where I can get my spaghetti Bolognese.
因为那才是我来的目的 它在哪
‘cause that's why I'm here for. Where is it?
带着这个问题 我们出发了
And with that, we were off.
显然 我不需要呆在车棚下
Obviously,I don't need to be in the shade because
因为我有地中海式的橄榄肤色
I have a Mediterranean olive complexion.
于是我打开650S的顶棚 也不怕太阳烤
That means I can take the roof off the 650S and not suffer at all.
真棒
Excellent.
说实话
I'll be honest,
我有点嫉妒漂亮的敞篷迈凯伦
that I am slightly annoyed by how good that McLaren looks with the roof off.
突然间它有了超跑的炫酷元素 看着真棒
Suddenly it's got all that drama you need in the supercar. It looks brilliant.
该死
Damn.
到了 我们进入博洛尼亚的中心 赤色之城
And here we are, entering the center of Bologna,the red city,
这样叫它 是因为是意大利共产党的大本营
so-named because it's the communist capital of Italy,
而且是兰博基尼的故乡
and it's the home of Lamborghini.
该死的共产主义的象征
That communist icon.
在市中心我们停好车 没造成一点轰动
In the city center we parked in a square which caused no fuss at all.
很高兴见到你 保重
- Nice to meet you,take care.
-我为我朋友抱歉 -哦我真得走了
– I apologize for my friend, -Oh, I'd really like to go now.
他 他饿的时候就不太正常
he's… he gets crotchety when he's hungry.
我没病我只是想吃东西
I'm not crotchety I just wanna go and eat.
-我能去找找吗 -好的去吧
- Can I go and get it?  - Yes, you go.
好吧 我要 再见
Right, I'm gonna… bye.
-我要去 -你更喜欢哪个
- I'm gonna go and .. - Which one do you like best?
兰博基尼还是迈凯伦
Lamborghini or McLaren?
迈凯伦 迈凯伦
- McLaren.  – The McLaren?
耶
Yeah.
就算在这里 迈凯伦都比兰博受欢迎
McLaren more than the Lamborghini even here.
我能点份肉酱意面
I'll have these spaghetti Bolognese, please?
不不不
No. no, no.
请给我一份肉酱意面
I'll have spaghetti Bolognese, please.
波罗格纳的肉酱意面
Spaghetti Bolognese that's in Bologn…
不 没有意面
No. no spaghetti.
意大 利面 肉 不不不
- Spa… ghetti… Bologn…  - NOOOO.
不存在 这里没有肉酱意面
Not exist, there's no Spaghetti Bolognese.
确定？
Sure?
意面 没有
Spaghetti, no.
好吧
Ok.
最终 我只好承认失败
去找杰里米 他刚吃完晚餐
Eventually,I had to concede defeat,and join Jeremy,who just finished his dinner.
-晚上好 -哇哦
- Evening. -Wow
-真荒唐 -什么
- This is ridiculous.  – What?
你在哪都找不到肉酱意面
You can't get spaghetti Bolognese anywhere…
不能吗 在博洛尼亚
- Can you not?  - in Bologna.
不可思议 那你要了什么
- That's unbelievable.  – What have you had anyway?
我要了个 ragù
I had a ragù.
听着就恶心
Sounds disgusting.
不管了 听着 不管它
Anyway, listen, never mind that.
我预约了今晚的房间 我有个主意
I booked a hotel for tonight,and I've got an idea.
它只有一个好房间 好
- It's got one really good room, ok?  - Right.
谁第一个到谁就住进去
Whoever gets there first can have the room.
-那我们就比赛 -对
- So we'll race there…  - Yeah.
-第一个到的入住 -没错
- first one there gets that room.  – Yeah. Rally.
好 那我做好准备了
Alright. Yeah I'm up for that.
你同意了 好 让我吃完 然后我们出发
You're up for that? Alright, I just finish it, and we can get going.
肉酱意面
Spaghetti Bolognese.
Ragù.
3, 2, 1, 出发
3, 2, 1, go.
卫星导航在这
Sat nav is the answer here.
好的 点进去
So, that, put it in.
就这样
Here we go.
不知道他要去哪
Don't know where he is going.
当然 哈蒙德不知道的是 在这样的老城
What Hammond doesn't realize,of course,is that in old cities like this,
即便是奥迪的卫星导航都无济于事
even Audi's satellite navigation is useless.
当地地理知识才是你需要的 而我正好拥有
Local knowledge, that's what you need, and I know it is right here.
我很喜欢这种把卫星导航整合到仪表板的做法
I love the way the sat nav is integrated into the main instrument binnacle
而不是丑陋的分成两块屏幕
rather than a separate ugly screen.
好 呃 呃
Ok, er… er…
好像 我觉得走那儿
sort of... I think it's that way
当哈蒙德在惹恼当地的快递小哥时
while Hammond was annoying local delivery drivers
我用老派的做法奔向目标
I was making progress the old fashioned way
棒极了 northdella街 开过这个大雕塑
good. so right on northdella, pass that big statue
恩 我知道我在哪了
yes I know where I am now
我比导航懂得多
I know more than satellite navigation
好吧 是个人都比麦克拉伦的导航厉害
well everyone knows more than McLaren's satellite navigation
因为 它真的是啥也不会
because it knows... literally nathing at all
它能告诉你去过哪
it tells you where you've been
想去哪
it tells you where you think you want to be
但就是没法告诉你在哪 往哪去
but never tells you where you are or where are you going
这可不能左转
it's not left here
我要直走
shraight on
啊要右转要右转
no it was right it was right
这里应该右转才对
it should down the right there
大部分超跑在城里
事实上所有超跑都显得又大又笨
in cities most supercars in fact all supercars feel enormous and ungainly
驾驶它们就像牵着公牛逛瓷器店
they really do feel like you going into a china shop with a bull
这车不同 它像紧缩在你周围一样 显得很小只
this though it doesn't it shrinks around you it feels tiny
说到小只的那个
and speaking of Hammond
天啊 要是能选宽点的路就好了
god,it would be able to select width of street
这样的车宽 真不好判断
it's really hard to judge this car
这里挤进去
squeeze it down here
轻轻松松
easy-peasy
骑车的 我完全不知道他在那儿
cyclist I have no idea he was there
他在我盲区里 巨大的盲区里
he was in my blind spot which is massive
恩 穿过这?
oh,through here?
不 左转?
no,left？
到啦 天了撸
this is it aw god
好吧 我就不要那间了
well i don't want the part room anyway
随便哪间就行 我没那么快
any room woud do me I'm not that fast
不就是个房间么
it's just a room
哦我听到了一只"鼹鼠"接近的声音
oh I hear the sound of an approaching Hammond
他应该还有九层要跑
think he's still nine stories away
足够看完这本书
so we have plenty of book to finish my book
声音越来越响了
he's getting louder
啊哈 你来啦
a-ha you're here
为毛赢了这个要开心啊
why is the winner gonna be very pleased
哦 因为这个旅馆就这一间房 你瞧
well this hotel has only one room and as you can see
我住里面了
I've got it
一间房 还能叫旅馆么
one room it's not really a hotel is it?
这就是家一间房的旅馆
it is a one-room hotel
所以你的意思是
so what do you say
我得和你同床共枕
I got to sleep with you
没门
which is not gonna happen
就是啊
no it's not
因为我会像这样睡
cos I will sleep like that
画面太美我不想看
don't wanna know
或者我得提着行李原路返回 另找旅馆
or go all the way back down with my suitcases and find somewhere else
没错
I say exactly yes
输家 滚粗
you lose back you go
好吧 我走
right go
睡个好觉 别挂了啥的
yeah sleep well hope you don't die or something
没事我能找个别的好地方
I'll be fine I'll find somewhere good
别绊着了
don't trip on
下山总比上山难
it's much more tricky going down than its going up
最差我也能睡医院里
oh at least I'm going to sleep in hospital
第二天早上 被房间唯一的窗外豪景所启迪
the next morning inspired by the incredible views from my hotels only bedroom window
我有个好主意
I had an idea
一个想要和我那坏脾气同事分享的好主意
an idea I was going to show with my Robert Grumpet collegue
干嘛
what
事情是这样的
well the thing is okay
离这不到50英里的地方
50 miles from here not even there
有一条赛道
there's a racetrack
什么赛道
what racetrack
我不知道名字 但赛道门口有个大大的红头盔
don't know what it's called but there's a big red helmet at the entrance
让我猜猜
let me guess
赛道上只能容下一辆车
theres's only room for one car on the racetrack
不
no
然后你第一个到
and you're on it first
不 事实上
No,honestly if you
我觉得我们应该去那
I wish we could go there
真该去一趟
no we should
真是条赛道 没错
-it's a proper race  -yes it is
-是的 -好吧
-it is  -all right
只要找红头盔就行
Just look for a red helmet
red helmet红头盔 在有男性生殖器尖端之意
探路开始了
an so the search began
不好意思 红头盔在哪
mi scusi dove è il elmetto rosso
他们都不知道啊哈蒙德
they don't seem to know,Hammond
你问他们啥了
what are you asking
红头盔在哪
mi scusi dove è il elmetto rosso
这不就是问他们红头盔在哪吗
did that mean you're asking them where the red helmet is
是啊
oh yeah
这好像有点鲁莽啊
that might be a bit rude actually
在不断寻找之后
eventually after fine tuning italian
终于找到了
we found it
哈蒙德你同意么
would you agree Hammond that
这是一个红头盔
is a red helmet
这红头盔确实大
it's a very big red helmet yes
这是穆杰罗赛道
this is Mugello
不是世上最快的赛道
it's not the fastest racetrack in the world
也不是最有技术挑战性的
or the most tecnical
但绝对是
but it sure is hell
最美的赛道
the prettiest
而这些是我们拿来遛弯的车
and these are the cars we driving around it
我选了新款的宝马M4
I had a go on for the new BMW M4
哈蒙德选了个V8的
and Hammond had chosen the V8
捷豹F-Type coupe R
the Jaguar F-Type coupe R
一辆他不怎么喜欢的车
a car he doesn't like very much
为啥啊
why don't you like it
我觉得它不怎么好看
well I don't think it's pretty
但别人都说好
cause everyone says yes
好看啊
it is
我不觉得啊
I don't think it is
我也不喜欢它的声音
and I don'k like the noise it makes
乒乒乓乓的排气声
all that crackles and bangs
它们是人造的
they're artificial cause they're a man with
是电脑让车发出这声音
the laptop told it to sound like that
V6版的声音还不错
V6 is not bad
V8版的PIAPIAPIA声
but the V8 bababababa
都是假的
it's false
好 你本来有选择
so,ok you had a choise
你能选任何一辆你喜欢的车
you can have any car you like
为什么选这辆你不喜欢的
why do you brought somthing you don't like
过会你就知道了
you shall see
话音刚落 他就走了
and with that he was gone
听听
listeh to that
听着像消化不良
sounds it's got an indigestion
当你收油的时候
and when you lift off
大部分人听到车发出这个声音
most peole hear a car making noise like that
都会觉得车坏了
nothing gets broken
不喜欢这内饰
don'k like the interior
仪表指针很无聊
I think the dials are boring
把灯光控制集成在转向控制器上
putting the light control on the end of the indicator stock
在日产马驰上没问题
fine in Nissan Micro
但这是辆9万5千英镑的跑车啊
but this is a 95,000 pounds sports car
要不是捷豹懒 就是他们故意不愿意
it suggests they're too lazy or too mean
为这车新开发个控制器
to develop a second swich for it
而且我觉得它太贵了
and I think it's too expensive
你花9万5千英镑 自然想让它面面俱到
let's put a 95,000 pounds  when you expect it can do everything acceptable
不久以前这价钱能买超跑了
not so long ago that's a supercar money
太贵了
and it's too much
它再便宜点就好了
it should be all together cheaper
到底为什么我会为穆杰罗赛道
so why then have I chosen this car
选这辆车
for my day at the Mugello
简单
simple
它比宝马的马力更大
because it' s more powerful than the BMW
而且它能干这活
and it can do this
有些车能把它改得容易转向过度 更好漂移
some cars can be made to oversteer to drift and slide
这台车
this wants to
骨子里想漂移
it's all it wants to do
连我都能这样漂
even I can drift this
我可是个傻子啊
and I'm an idiot
这就是台小流氓 这货算是辆捷豹
it's just a hooligan machine it might be a Jaguar
但绝不是辆自命不凡的车
but it ain't no stuff sure
几个我不喜欢这辆宝马的理由
one or two things I don't like about the BMW
这丑恶的颜色还不是主要原因
not just the color which of course it's hidious
实际上 这车
see the thing is in nesonse
是辆双门版M3
this is a two-door M3
以前我们管它叫M3双门版
what used to be called the M3 coupe
现在叫M4
but now the've called it a BMW M4
宝马的人想着 我们要让它与众不同
and they thought "right we must make it different"
只在这片区域
and look how much styling it is
就有这么多样式
in that bit of car
再看车前盖
and look at the bonnet it goes
它往上 往上
up there and up again
再往上 瞧这后视镜
and up again the door mirror
为什么要这么花哨
why is it so farsy?
你会觉得
you get the impression that
如果让设计它的人 来设计安洁莉娜朱莉
if a man who styled this will given the job of styling Angelina Jolie
她的眼睛很漂亮嘛
even so she got lovely eyes
老子给她6个
so i'll give eh six of those
再来上14个鼻子
and fourteen noses
23对嘴唇
and twenty three lips
这完全不对啊
and it would't have worked
更糟糕的是
and there is more
哈蒙德的捷豹里塞着V8
Richard's Jag that has a V8
老款M3里塞着V8
the old M3 has a V8
这只是3升6缸增压发动机
this has a 3 liter turbocharged six
话糙了点 但是涡轮增压是弱者开的
I'm sorry but turbocharger is for the weak
我知道这样排放少了 北极熊开心了
I know it's very good for a missions in polar bears and so on
但这样就有涡轮迟滞
but that has to to be lag that has to to be a gap
从你脚踩下去 到车子往前走
between when you put your foot down
总有时间差
and the car moving forward
完全没办法
there has to be
虽然感觉不到但肯定有迟滞啊
can't feel it but it must be there
绝对的
it must
输家
loooser
好吧
very good
还有个环保相关的问题 它装了电子助力转向
there's another eco issue is that they fitted electric power steering
那是这台车最不该装的
whatever you do you can never ever ever
把转向设定在运动+模式
put the steering in sport plus
方向盘会像个开关一样
because it's like a swich
转向过度 开 关 开 关
over steer on-off on-off
现在我把它设定好了
right now i'm gonna set up
变速箱在火力全开模式
gearbox in maximum attack mode
悬挂在火力全开模式
suspension in maximum attack
转向 最舒适模式
steering maximun comfort
这就行了
then it will work
看到没
see easy now
简单多了
much easier
撸呜呜呜瑟
and loooser
啊不错啊哈蒙德不错
yes very good Hammond very good
但这些鸡毛蒜皮背后
but behind all the little niggles
有一个不容置疑的事实
there is one inescapable truth
老M3跑完一公里要24秒
the old M3 did standard kilometer in 24 seconds
这货 22秒
this does it in 22
但M4最让人印象深刻的还不是速度
but it's not the speed that impresses most of all the M4
是操控之精准
it's the percision of the handling
是这么回事
The thing about this is that
车身由铝合金和碳纤维构架而成
It's all held together with a lattice work aluminum carbon-fibre
十分坚固
It's incredibly stiff
你感受得到
You can feel that
那感觉之美妙 坐好出发 仔细感受
Just wonderful sense, you adjust the back starting to go
它的路感堪称完美
And it's all communicated beautifully
当然前提是你调对的话
If you set it up right
渣渣
loser
我受够了
I've had enough of this
哈蒙德那张脸好欠揍
As always becoming weary with cheery Hammond
我把他叫到修理区 来个鸿门宴
I invited him into the pits for lunch and an argument
你怎么吃饼干了
Why you eating biscuits?
额这边没有肉酱意面
They haven't got spaghetti bolognaise, have they?
但是有意式肉酱啊
Well, have Ragù
我不想吃那个 -看着很萌啊
I don't want Ragù. It's lovely.
听起来很吓人
It sounds awful.
你会喜欢的 我才不
You like it. I don't like it.
-那车很快诶 -对 但是...
That's quick. Yeah, but...
跟那辆比起来就无聊多了
It's a bit boring compared with that way.
这个跟老款M3完全不是同一种生物
This is the different animal to previous M3 Coupe
完全不同 你知道涡轮增压电子转向什么的
It's definitely different,you know the turbo charging,the electric steering
让这车风格独特 但还是略显严肃
they really made it very different. But it is still a serious player.
不过确实很快
It's properly quick.
你说得对
You get...get it right.
诶你刚刚用什么词来着 -啥 -严肃 -对
And what was that word you just used? What? Serious. Yep.
确实有点 不苟言笑 从头到尾都太严肃
It is a bit serious.There is a weave of serious.It's taking it all seriously.
这辆依然是捷豹 但至少它有灵气 很完整
That might be a Jag. But it's mental. It's complete
是个疯子 真心... 连我都能滑得很顺溜
It's a lunatic.It really...even I can slither about in that and sort it out
前轮抓地太结实 后面就滑得飞起
It's got a sticky front and a lose back end.
这不正讨人喜欢么 对
And who doesn't like that. Yeah.
但是肯定不适合初次约会 不 我倒是喜欢...
Not a phrase for first date obviously. No, exactly but I do like...
我觉得我们... 我正等着呢
I thought we were...I wasn't expecting that
总算轻松了
Freed from that sort of thing
鉴于你们的对话过于无趣
As this argument is getting boring
还好啊 我觉得蛮有聊的
Not really. I was enjoying it.
我们设计了个挑战来看看你们哪辆车更好
We've devise a challenge to see which of your cars is best,
你们要与试替哥比赛
you are now race the Stig.
真的? -对 他驾驶菲亚特500阿巴斯
Really? Yeah, he will be driving a Fiat 500 Abarth
哇哦 是一辆小钢炮
Wow. It seems a hatchback
他会先跑两分半钟
He would be given a two and a half minutes start
谁先超过他谁赢
First one to pass him wins
超过他? 额 就是说要打败他?
Pass him? Well, as when he is there overtake him?
就是说让我们打败试替哥?
You mean we've got overtake the stig?
这在技术理论上可行么?
Is that technically, physically possible?
这就像穿越虫洞 踏入未知
Stepping into the unknown. It's like going through a worm hole.
没错
Right
于是 心情沉重 眼睛圆睁的我们
So, with heavy hearts and wide eyes,
车子挨着试替哥停在了起跑线上
we lined our cars on the start line next to the Stig.
绿灯 走起
On the green. OK.
垃圾
Rubbish.
这是他最好的一次了
That was his best shot.
两分半 你看已经开始下雨了
Two and half minutes.You see it's been raining.
对 我已经发现了
Yes, I am aware of this.
杰里米 我有点害怕
Jeremy, I'm a bit scared.
我还有好多东西要调 对
I've got many things to set up. Yes.
变速箱 暴力模式
In drive gearbox, violent settings.
好 捷豹 你得乖乖的
Ok, Jag, I need you to behave.
转向 舒适
Steering, comfort
好样的
Lovely.
天 我已经看到他了
Oh, god, I've actually seen him.
是时候了 出发
This is it, here we go.
摩擦 摩擦
Struggling for traction.
我去 我开始就搞得一团糟
Oh, deary me, I've made a mess of all that.
这可是最强劲的车子 看我秀下操作
This is the most powerful car. I stand a very rare chance of doing this.
哈蒙德开了个好头 他还...
Hammond got a better start. He also has…
一个残忍的事实是 他的车
Let's be brutally honest about this,
比我的多130马力
about 130 more house power than I do
简单粗暴 想象自己是个赛车手 理查德
And let's be neat and crisp, think like a racing driver, Richard.
不过问题是 我不太擅长赛车
而且我觉得这车子也不想这样跑
Problem is,I'm not very good at doing that,and the car I don't think wants to.
我需要的是精准的操控 所有动作都由我掌控
What I need now is precision.That all have to come from me,
我现在完全没有任何精准度可言
which means I've had it, because I don't have any precision
看我 切弯 走平整干净的路线
Look,turning in, just focus on tidy clean lines.
一路上滑来滑去 这样跑不快额
Not sliding all the way round like this. This is not helping anything
不要滑 不要滑
Sliding is not good, sliding won't help.
那捷豹是快 但是尾巴一直甩来甩去
That Jag is fast, but it's waggling its tail all over the shore.
该死 该死 该死
Damn, damn, damn.
他吃上草了 哈我咬住他了
He is on the grass. Oh, I've got him here surely.
哈哈
Haha.
天 那宝马有两下子
God, that BMW got some go.
不要滑啊 千万别
Sliding will not help. Mustn't do it.
现在专心手头的任务
Just concentrate on the job in hand,
追上试替哥 然后超过他
which is catching the Stig,and then passing him.
有人说 如果他被打败 他会气得下蛋
Some says that if he is ever overtaken,he will actually lay an egg.
很多圈之后
还是看不到那小菲亚特的踪迹
Still, no sign of the little fiat,
我都不敢相信我的眼睛 他消失了
I can scarcely believe my eyes,it's just not anywhere to be seen.
尼玛试替哥跑哪去了
Where the hell is the stig?
啊他在这 就在他的小菲亚特里
There he is. There he is in his little fiat.
杰里米赶上他了 那就是试替哥
Jeremy is on him. There is the Stig.
他只有165马力 我有425 进入射程了
165 house power he's got. I've got 425.he is in range.
杰里米正试图超越 试替哥在阻挡他 没成功 他要
Jeremy is trying to get pass.He is blocking him.He is not having it,is he
现在他正在左右晃 化身马尔多纳多
Now he is waeving around. He's been Maldonado.
啊我超不过杰里米
Oh, no I can't get pass Jeremy.
想超我没门 挡着你
Not sideways. I'm stop Hammond,
我这样赶不上试替哥啊
which means I can't get pass the Stig if I'm doing that.
理查德 没用的
Oh, Richard, that's not helping.
哦 啊
Oh, oh.
啊 我失控了 尼玛
Oh, I've span. Oh, shit.
尼玛 我搞砸了
Oh, shit. Oh, dear. I've done a bad thing.
我没法否认 我撞了
I'm not denying it. I've crashed.
我们知道 我看见你飞出去了
Yes, we know, I saw you go off.
我弄坏了车子 为啥受伤的总是我
I broke the car, it's always me, always me.
不需要担心哈蒙德了
No need to worry about Hammond any more.
追上他
Go get him.
啊我现在倒觉得杰里米在为团队奋斗了
Yeah, I like to think that Jeremy is doing that for the team now.
好 看我追它
Right, go get him.
我来了
Here I come.
往右晃一下再左走
Faint right go left.
我快超过你了 试替哥
We are going to do now, Stig
我抓住你了 把你卡在外面
Yes, I've got you. I've got you stuffed out there.
他的每一根纤维都在散发着怒气
Rage is emanating from every fibre of his being.
因为他知道 他将成为历史
Cos he knows, he is history.
胜利在我手
Victory is mine.
待会见哈蒙德 得摆出我的标志性表情
When I see Hammond, practice my face.
好吧 但是 说嘛 感觉什么样的? 超过试替哥的感觉
Alright, but, come on, what's it like? Actually overtaking the Stig.
额有点奇怪 就像神秘博士的特殊效应
Well, it's strange. Because it's like a Doctor Who special effect.
就像是时间和空间 他们在运动
It's like a space and time. They move.
像时空隧道?
Was it like a tunnel?
听到没
You can hear, oh?
他过来了
Here he comes now.
他来了
There he is.
有点奇怪 因为这从没发生过
This is a bit weird. Cos this never happened.
他一辈子都没发生过 他从未被打败
No, it's never happened in his entire life. He's never been overtaken.
我猜他现在应该心情不好
I think he is probably in a bad mood.
-他才不会心情不好
-我是说他才没什么心情 -他可是试替哥
He won't be in bad mood. I mean he doesn't get any mood. He is the Stig.
我们只是...
We just live…
他的肢体语言向来糟糕
It is known that his body language is bad.
看起来不像是...
We are not looking like a…
他很好 他没事...
He is alright, he is ok…
不 他很愤怒
No, he is bully
我很惊讶 那...
I'm surprised, that's…
这... 来我们看看这个...
This, that's…let's look at this
这个看起来就像是蹭过地毯的小狗鼻子
Please, that looks like a puppy have its nose rubed in the carpet.
看你撞坏了这块面板 对的
So you've done this panel. Yes.
你还撞坏了 这边一块
You've also done, I notice, you've done this panel.
对 这边这块
Yup. This panel here.
还有门
And the door.
所以现在该闪人了
Sp it's time to move on now. It is.
恩对
Hum…yes, please.
你应该想开下宝马
You'd like a ride in the BMW.
是的
Yes, please.
啊尼玛的
Oh, for God's sake.
太幼稚了
That's childish, isn't it?
第二天早餐后 我们决定
The next morning, over breakfast, we decided not to do the next leg of our journey
抛弃那辆侧面喷了绅士香肠的车子
in a car with a gentleman sausage painted on the side.
这里是托斯卡纳 我在想该开什么车
This is Tuscany, I'm trying to think what car, we should be using here.
因为这里是新工党可爱的精神家园 比如布莱尔啊...
Cos it's sort of new labour,lovely,spiritual home,you know,Tony Blair
什么合适
What a fit
混动
Hybrid.
只有环保的才能与这边的情境完美契合
You've got to blend in, you've got use something that is eco-friendly.
对 我们开混动车 好啊
Yeah, we will drive a hybrid. Ok
吃有机蔬菜和泥土
We'll eat organic vegetables and mud.
我们也不用肥皂了
We won't use soap while we are here.
拿树叶蔽体就好
We will just use leaves.
我正想换一种全新的生活方式
I'm looking forward to trying a new life style.
这辆车就是我们开的混动车
This would be the hybrid we'd be driving.
环保的迈凯轮P1
The tree-hugging McLaren P1.
我们正开着一辆电动车行驶在机车道上
We're actually on a motorway in an electro drive.
128km/h
That's 80 miles an hour.
毫不费力啊
Really not trying.
人们经常问如果电动车占据主流了 我们该怎么办
People go on about what are we gonna do when electric cars come along.
在寂静中飞驰
Drive like a maniac in silence.
只用电池都比高尔夫GTI快
It's quicker than a Golf GTI just using its batteries.
如果你厌烦了这安静的环境
And when you get bored with the sound of silence,
那就唤醒那台V8吧
you just turn on the V8 sound track.
唔 这声浪真动听
Woo, we make some good noises.
感受到那强大的扭矩了没 真是太快了
You feel the torque then? It is properly fast.
驾驶大多数车子 你都随时能油门全开
Most cars you can use full throttle pretty much whenever you want.
这车不行 如果你打算踩地板油
Well, this, you just can't. if you use full throttle in this.
你必须胸有成竹
You need to be pretty certain
会跑的飞快
There is a big run off.
对 快得没边
Yeah, there is run offs everywhere.
天 这转向简直是...
God, the steering in this is just…
你会觉得它似乎在瞬移 对
Yeah, you can feel it darts. Absolutely.
这轮胎好带感
Must feel amazing at the wheel.
必须的
It does. Hum.
你知道超跑在这种颠簸路很恼火
Also the way, you know bumps can often upset supercar .
但是这悬架很好的解决了这个问题
But because the suspension in this, they just don't.
-开起来感觉不错 -好
Glad it feels good to drive. Good.
听到这很是欣慰啊
Really really pleased to hear that.
为啥不是我开?
Why aren't I driving?
我还没开过呢 该我了
Well, I've never driven it. It's my go.
昨天你开540马力都撞了
Yesterday, you have 540 horse powers. And you crashed.
这货有904马力
This has 904.
我不会撞的
I won't crash it.
我跟你说吧 什么?
So I tell you what. What?
这车真不错 别具一格
It's really good. It doesn't feel like any other supercar.
不一样? 对
Does it not? No.
我没开过怎么知道什么感觉
I don't know how it feels because I've never driven it.
为了不让哈蒙德继续抱怨
To trying put an end to Hammond's moaning.
开这么慢是想让我开吗? 才不是
you'll gonna let me drive. Is that why you are slowing? No.
我决定在葡萄园停下 试试盲品
I decided to stop off at a vineyard for some blind wine tasting.
-红酒 -不 这是白的
Red. No, it's white.
这尼玛 -抱歉哥们
Oh, dame it! I'm sorry, mate.
好 咱们试试这个 拿好
Right, let's try this one, hang on.
尝出来没?
Got it?
啤酒 错 那是红酒 -啊再来一杯
Beer. No, it's red. Yeah, one more, one more.
尝出来没
What are you getting?
-红酒 -不对差不多 这是调过的
Red. No, well, nearly, redbull. it was diet though.
看嘛 你蒙上眼了
You see, you are blinded.
我去 真是红牛
Really, redbull.
-嘿 -啥
Hey. What.
-你喝酒了 -对啊 -那你不能开车咯
You swallowed the wine. Yeah. You can't drive.
我什么都没碰
I haven't had anything.
我倒酒 你喝酒 你不能开车
I've been pouring, you've been drinking. You cannot drive.
-你故意的 -不是啊
You did that on purpose. No.
上车 快点上车
Get in the car. Come on, get in.
我刚发现一个小问题
There was however a small problem that I just thought of.
啊我的背 我进不去啊
Oh, my back. I can't get in.
进来啊 不行
Get in the car. I can't.
进来 我进不来 -进来啊 -不行你看
Just get in the car. I can't. Get in.I am not, look
我的背啊
Ooh, my back again.
幸运的是 我选择了一条最安全的道路回旅馆
Luckily, though, I've chosen the safest route to the hotel.
你开的比我想象中慢得多啊 好极了
You are a lot slower than I thought you would be, it's quite good.
剩下的都是这样的路吗
Is it like this all the way this afternoon?
谁说的 是不是
Who said? Is it?
还好答案是 是
Happily the answer was yes.
得了吧 开这一路简直要把我逼疯了
Oh, come on, I've been desperate to have a go in this.
想想 你可以说你开过迈凯轮P1啊
You'll be able to say you've driven the McLaren P1, think of that.
干得好 我是说 你没撞坏
Well done, we just say, no, you didn't crash once.
啊 好吧 我说
Yea, alright, well, tell you what.
我得来一大盘肉酱意面庆祝一下
I'm gonna celebrate that with a big plate of spaghetti bolognaise.
祝你好运 好 在里面
Good luck with that. Yes, in there.
你们有? -我想应该是
Is it in there? Yep, I think so.
第二天早晨 杰里米想去参观那些陈年旧楼
The next morning, Jeremy had planned a visit to see some more old buildings.
但是我想出了个更好的点子
But I'd come up with something much much better.
如果要跑拉力赛 我就杀了你
If this involves rallying, I'm going to kill you.
不 不
It doesn't, it isn't.
但是你看这么松散的地面
No, but Hammond this is a loose surface.
闻起来也像要越野
And that smells rallying to me.
别怕 不是这回事
Fear not, this is something else.
那是啥 你肯定听过一千英里耐力赛
What? You will have heard of the Mille Miglia.
嗯 貌似是开着1952年的阿尔法罗密欧
跑一千英里穿越意大利什么的
Yep, thousand miles through Italy in something like a 1952 Alfa Romeo?
这就是我们要做的 真的?
That is what we are going to do. Really?
-我改了点东西 -改了啥? 距离
Well, I have to change a few things. What things? The distance.
我缩小了一点
I've brought it down a bit.
-多远? -6.4公里
How far is it? It's 4 miles.
-所以是迷你耐力赛
So it's the Quattro Miglia
这标题不错 嗯 就它了
Snappy title like that, yes,it`s that.
是开着1952年的阿尔法罗密欧么
Is it in 1952 Alfa Romeos?
不 我们这回开法拉利
No, we are doing it in Ferraris.
-真的? -对啊 跟我来 过来看看
Really? Yes, come with me, come have a look.
什么法拉利? 过来看
What Ferraris? Have a look, come with me.
看 你的车
your car Ferrari 355
法拉利355
there it is
我一看
I know
就觉得有点不对
immediately I could see something was wrong
这货到底是啥
what is it
其实呢 这是一台套了355壳的Fiero
it's a Fiero underneath bury deep under the Ferrari styling
这是台庞蒂亚克？
it's a Pontiac
是滴
yup yup
那么说这是台庞蒂亚克
it's a Pontiac that is styled by someone in the garage
被一个穷的连媳妇都跑了的
his wife's left him
敲出来的手工版法拉利355么
to look bit like a Ferrari 355
是的
yes
我以前买过那一款
a car I used to own
我的神啊
oh for god's sake
好吧 我们发动
right we gonna fire it up
耶 听这动静
yeah listen to that
皮带有点打滑啊
the belt's slippy
这是台V6
that's a V6
是的
yeah it is
没错的话就是原装的Fiero引擎啊
so on for memory it's a Fiero engine yeah
恩 没错
it is yeah
嗯 V6 140匹马力
V6 140 housepower those engines had
嗯 差不多
yeah about
就算后面印了"F335berlinetta"也还不是法拉利啊
just cos it says F355 berlinetta on the back doesn't make it
就像我在你后背上写个布拉德皮特
if I stencil the words Brad and Pitt on the back of you
你还是不是他啊
it doesn't make you Brad Pitt
至少木耳上车功能还是有嘛
No,but for a moment it might fool someone
想看我的么
you wanna see mine
你的是个啥
what is it
过来看
come and have a look
特斯塔罗萨哦
a Testarossa yeah
侧面还有标志性的肋条哦
it's got the steaks on the side
所有设计元素一应俱全
all the styling cues in there look
看那坨伸出来的
look that overhang
哈哈 原版的已经很大的 但这个的要更大
yeah but it was big on the original and even bigger on this one
-哈蒙德  -啥事儿
Hammond --yeah
你别介意哦 看 这明显是塑料
因为所有的拼装车都用塑料
forgive me OK this is obviously plastic cos all kit-cars are
但是你看过框架是用
have you seen this framework is made from
-用的是4×2尺寸的木头 -没错
-4×2 -yes，it's 4×2
用木头的么
it's wood
和订制车厢一样嘛
well some organs'in it a couch built that
这是扣上去的塑料壳子
it's a fence with some plastic on it
这是神马
what is that
这是丐中丐Fiero用的4缸机
that's the original the original Fiero had a 4 cylinder engine in it
2.5升么 -是的
2.5 liter -- yeah
有多少马力
how many housepower is that
92匹
所以说这就是一台92匹的特斯塔罗萨么 -回答正确
so it is a 92 housepwer Testarossa -- Yup
哦 特斯塔罗萨 4缸
Ohhhh Testarossa 4 cylinder
大灯 -一边能动
headlamps -- one works
于是我决定去试试
I then decided to see how far away
到底站多远 它才像真的特斯塔罗萨
you'd have to stand for it to look like a real Testarossa
亲 这看起来还是不像
so not mate that's still not Testarossa
嗯 确实不像 我觉得得往后再挪几步
no that's not quite that I think further another couple of steps back
行了吧 这下看起来像一台特斯塔罗萨了
come on from here that could be a testarossa
确实 但也可能是一个电话亭
yes but it could also be a phonebox
我不得不说 只要还能看的见
but --I'm sorry so long as it's occupying a pixel
他就不可能是特斯塔罗萨
it couldn't be a Ferrari Testarossa
耶 哈蒙的4英里砂砾路面
yeah here we go ignore girl Richard Hammond 4 mile long gravel
塑料版庞提亚克法拉利挑战赛 即将开始
plastic Pontiac-Ferrari kit-car challenge is about to begin
3 2 1 出发
Tre Due Uno Vai
哦 比赛开始
ohhh we are off
这台强劲的V6起步惊人啊
yes the mighty V6 is off to an amazing start
那台4缸的特斯塔罗萨被远远的甩到了身后
and the 4 cylinder Testarossa has been left far behind
事实上 我早就想参加一场一千英里古董车耐力赛
the thing is I have always wanted to do the Mille Miglia
因为我这个伯明翰佬从来没有被邀请过
but well I never get invited because I am a Brummie yob
但是要是邀请我 我也不参加 因为没时间
but maybe if I have be invited I haven't got the time
开完1000英里要花好几年呢
1000 miles takes ages
这个4英里迷你版
this Quattro Miglia I got time
我倒是有时间
and the spectators they get to see
眼下法拉利的比赛难得一见的
Ferraries racing in ways you never normally would
我去 这里有点滑啊
shiiii that was a bit skippy no antilock breaks
没有ABS 没有牵引力控制 没有任何驾驶辅助
no traction control no driver aids of any kind
全凭你的脚下功夫
just pure push-rock technology
为什么哈蒙德不能构思一个我可能喜欢上的汽车运动
why can't Richard Hammond ever dream up a motorsport that I might like
杰里米的车掉了一块
Jeremy's lost a piece of the car
指望这玩意儿能挺过4英里
expecting this to last 4 miles is expecting a fake Rolex you bought
就像在香港的杂货店里买的假劳力士
你还指望4次澡后它能存活
for a fiver at a market store in Hong Kong to last 4 trips to the shower
肯定会坏啊
it won't it will break
哦 又掉了一块
oh another piece of the car
不 动力在下降
oh no losing power
很多乒乓乒乓的声音
many bangs big bangs there
好起来啊 走啊
clear your throat car clear your throat and go
后轮锁死了
and we've locked up the rear wheels
嗯 情况不妙啊
yeah that's not good
动也动不了
and there's nothing at all now
幸运的是355病情危急
fortunately the 355 was in a terrible state
发动机把自己给煮了 发电机也坏了
the engine cooked itself and the alternator has stopped alternating
不幸的是居然能修
unfortunately however it was all fixable
好多小时后 我终于完成了
and many hours later I was able to finish
哈蒙德的愚蠢小比赛
Hammond's stupid little race
好的  -干得漂亮
yes -- well done
4英里哦 -没错
4 miles -- oh yeah
4英里挑战赛完成 哈哈哈
4 miles completed Mille Miglia is at the end yeeees
恭喜成功晋级第二关
you have made it to stage 2
啥
what
拉力赛只是第一关啦
well while you were finishing the massive
完成后解锁下一关
endurance feat you and car stage1
这就是第二关
this is stage 2
第二关是啥啊
what is stage 2
在你修车的时候
well while you were gone
在这优美的托斯卡纳小镇里 我画了条赛道
I worked out a lap around these buildings in this beautiful old Tuscany town
嗯 要跑多少圈呢
well how many laps
能跑多少圈就跑多少圈
as many as you can manage
那最后还在动的就是赢家么
well the last one still running is the winner
是的 -我还是去撞墙好了
yeah -- I'm gonna drive it into a wall
这就是我圈的赛道
this was the stage I had lined up
在一个废弃的托斯卡纳小镇里
it was round a stunning deserted Tuscany village
哈哈 看好了
OK this is it
你不会用一辆真的法拉利这么干
you wouldn't do this in a normal Ferrari
但用山寨版的
but you do it in this one
就好多了
it's better
我以宙斯的屁眼发誓 小哥要跪了啊
how in the name of Zeus's butthole of I ended up doing this
斯堪的纳维亚式漂移
right scan-flip
从来没这么开过法拉利
never been done in a Ferrari before
哦 我啥都看不见了
oh can't see anything now
我又瞎 又热 又悲催
I'm blind I'm hot I'm miserable
屁都看不见
I can't see a thing
第二关的灰尘确实是问题
yeah the dust is a problem on this stage
但是也成了独一无二的体验
that's what makes it a unique event
突然间我有了个主意
then I had an idea
如果我追上他 把他撞出赛道
if I catch up to him and ram him off the track
那么他就输了 悲剧就结束了
then he will lose and the misery will be over
添乱啊 这是城市街道 又不是房车赛
that's not helping it's not supposed to be stock car racing it's city stage
看老纸撞他 撞死他
I'm ramming him I am ramming him
不要啊
no no no
这个 猩猩同学 这不是拆迁大奖赛
that's, Clarkson, is not a demolition derby
好歹我开的也是法拉利
I'm in a Ferrari
万幸的是 悲惨的很多圈后
mercifully as we wrecked up more and more laps
车的疲态逐渐显出
the tow on the cars started to show
直到哈蒙德的车终于无法承受了
untill eventually Hammond's Testarossa could take the punishment no longer
我看到蒸汽了
I see steam
听起来都不对啊
none of these is good sounds
我想哈蒙德的车跪了 我希望如此
I think Hammond's car is wounded I'm hoping it is
哦 加把劲啊
Oh come on
胜利属于我 甜蜜蜜啊
victory is mine and it tastes sweet
但是哈蒙德和我想法迥异
but Hammond thought differently
-这还没完 -我了个去
it's not over yet -- oh for crying out loud
这台机器是一台非常简单的4缸机
the heart of this machine that's a simple 4 cylinder engine
一瞬间所有金属会受热膨胀然后卡住
it has the moment he seized all the metal expanded and stuck
就像你这个岁数的人的后背
it's like you had a bad back at your age
所以让他休息一下降降温
let it get on easy give him a rest
有些部件就会松开 就能打着了
the parts will contract it'll fire up it will do just that
不过不是现在
not not now
那是什么时候
when is it going to do that
我会算出来的
I'll pick the moment
我擅长这个 会知道什么时候能打着
yeah I'm good at this I'm good at knowing when it'll start
能发动
it's gonna start
要是能发动 我就抹脖子
if that starts i'm gonna kill myself
吼吼吼  快上车 快 咱继续
oh hohoho get in get in come on
哈哈 太好了 我和发动机心有灵犀啊
oh yes that is mechanical sympathy I'm the one with the machine
因为这匹跃马的呼吸又正常了
because the prancing horse whisperer was right
比赛继续
the race was back on
我还坐在这里 还在刷圈
I'm still in this I'm still wrecking those laps
求跪啊 求跪
please break now please break
在很多圈之后 幸运之神终于向我微笑了
after many more laps the gods of good fortune finally decided to smile on me
发生了一场惨烈的事故
there has been an extraodinary accident
引擎被卡在全油门状态
the engine is jammed on full rev
卡在一档
it's in first gear
离合器被一个
and the clutch pedal is been held down
不知道哪来的扫帚卡住
by a broom I have no idea where that came from
幸运的是车被绳子拴在两个重物上固定了
luckily though,it is held in place by two ropes which attached two heavy objects
一边是装着水泥块的手推车 另一边是这栋楼
one is a wheel barrow with a concrete block in it the other is this building
让我担心的是绳子底下突然起火了
what worries me though is this small fire has broken out underneath this rope
如果绳子烧断 啪的一声 扫帚就会被手推车拽飞
now if it would snap the broom will be drag down by the wheel barrow
就会挂上档 车会冲向那座房子
the clutch will pin off and the car will roar off into that building
我不知道怎么阻止这一切
I've no idea how to stop this from happening
在这场事故中我只是乘客
I'm just a passenger in this accident
好好想啊 杰里米 你必须要做点什么
think Jeremy there must be something you can do
哦 不
oh no
亲 祝贺你赢了
well mate congratulations you win
发生什么了
what happened
不可思议的碰撞
extraordinary crash
都插到墙里去了
really hard into the wall
但是你没受伤啊
but you're not hurt
我被扔出来了
I'm thrown clear
很神奇 不知道怎么我就被扔出来 然后车撞墙了
amazing,I don't know how that happened I was thrown out and it's gone into the wall
你丫是故意的
you did this on purpose
才没有
I didn't
你故意放弃比赛 我赢得毫无意义
you deliberately thrown the race this is a hollow victory
那天在旅店里 出现了一条对哈蒙德极好的消息
that night at the hotel there was good news for Hammond
我希望他会重获笑容
that I hope might put a smile back on his face
你们做肉酱意面么
do you do spaghetti bolognaise
做 -你确定
yes -- you do.yes
好 那我来一份
well I'll have one please
我也来一份 要传统版的
I'll have a spaghetti bolognaise traditional spaghetti bolognaise
太棒了
perfect
终于
at last
完美
excellent
纳尼 这是神马
um what's this
肉酱意面啊
spaghetti bolognaise
才不是
it's not
肯定是
it is
不不不是
no it isn't
这是肉酱意面加香肠
it is spaghetti with sausage
在意大利语里 肉酱意面就是意面加香肠
in Italy, spaghetti bolognaise is spaghetti with sausage
看 真正的香肠哦
look actual sausage
为啥不叫意面配香肠呢 这才不是肉酱意面
why don't they call it spaghetti with... it's not spaghetti bolognaise
这就是肉酱意面
it's spaghetti bolognaise!
如果意大利人到英国要一份热食早餐
if Italian come to Britain ask for a cooked breakfast
你肯定不会给他一份煮天鹅吧
you don't give him cooked swan do you
你会给他一份培根煎蛋
you give him bacon and eggs it's not right
-吃了它  -不
-eat it -no
-这不对  -就是它
It`s not right.It is.
第二天一早 我们在美丽的锡耶纳城不远处醒来
the next morning we woke near the beautiful town of Siena
酒店外 制片人给我们带来了两台车
and outside our hotel the producers has provided two cars
穿梭于崎岖古老的街道中
that will take us in and around its narrow and medieval streets
这是新款迷你库珀S
there was the new Mini Cooper S
被哈蒙德抢了
which was shotgunned by Hammond
所以我只能开奥迪S1
and an Audi S1 which as a result, would be driven by me
我还以为是嘉年华ST和高尔夫GTI呢
I was expecting a Fiesta ST and a Golf GTI
担我们去年开过了
yeah，we drove those last year
所以这是替代品
so this is their replacement
好吧 挺有意思 我之前还从没开过S1
well it's quite interesting cos I've never driven a S1 before
我也没开过库珀S
and I've never driven a Cooper S so
所以这就是一趟探索之旅
so it will be a voyage into the unknown
是的
yes it will
走起
that's what it will be
我们都知道锡耶纳是一个兔子洞
all we did know is that Siena is a rabbit warren
里面有着无数条幽深的小巷
made up with 6.7 million narrow streets
城里面小车为王 而且越小越好
in a town like this size matters and the smaller the better
小的总是最好的
small is always best
这就是新款迷你让我纠结的地方
that's what troubles me about this new Mini
比老款长了10厘米 比奥斯丁原版长了65厘米
it's 10cm longer with the last model which is 65cm longer than the original Mini
所以说 这不是真正迷你
so it isn't really Mini
我不想在这里说教
I don't wanna sound like somebody's dad here
但什么时候他们才不用"迷你"这名字了?
but when are they going to stop calling it the Mini
就像年轻时叫你"小子"
so as a bloke you are called young man
叫了很多年 但总有一天没人会那么叫你
for a lot of years but the day comes and must come when nobody calls you young man anymore
因为你不年轻了
because you are not
也许因为它如此之大
and perhaps because it's so big
就需要更大的2升涡轮增压引擎
it needs a bigger 2 liter turbocharged engine
动力接近200匹马力
which develops neally 200 BHP
开起来比我想象的好多了
it feels a lot better than I expected to feel
感觉棒极了
it feels fantastic
感觉很高级 因为它确实很贵
it feels expensive which is as well because it is
杂七杂八的选配下来
with everything on it as this one has got
差不多得两万五千英镑
you'll be looking at best part of 25 thousand pounds
有些事不得不提
there are some other issues as well
这代之前的上代迷你
the old new Mini the one before this one
有很多呆萌的成分
had a sort of zany feel to it
速度表尺寸堪比你的大脸
had the massive speedo as big as your face
他们还把摇窗器按钮从门上拿下
they moved the window swiches out to the door
中间还有一坨圆的 但那不是仪表
they got this big round thing in the middle but it's not a dial anymore
是这样的屏幕
it has this screen
它试图又理性又疯癫
it's trying to be both sensible and a bit crazy
我呢 却一点不担心这台S1
I on the other hand had no worry at all about the Audi S1
因为从数据来看
because on paper at least
它蛮猛的
sounds like it could be a gem
一般来说 小钢炮是普通掀背 加更强劲的引擎
normally a hot hatchback is normal hatchback with a bigger engine
这台车确实有个高尔夫R一样的引擎
and this does indeed have the same engine as the Golf R
228匹 2升涡轮增压
228 hp 2 liter turbo
另外还是四驱
but it also has 4 wheel drive
那就代表把原本的扭力梁
and that meant removing the standard car's torsion beam
换成了多连杆
and replacing it with a full-link setup
就是说车的整个后部都要重新设计
which meat redesigning the entire rear end of the car
这肯定花了奥迪一大笔
that must have cost Audi a fortune
还有可调节减震器和六速手动
it also has adjustable dampers and a six speed manual gearbox,
就是说这是辆
so what you are looking at here is
228匹涡轮增压的紧凑四驱奥迪
a compact 228 horsepower four wheel drive turbo charged Audi.
这不就是老Quattro回归吗
Could it be then that the Quattro is back.
为了验证这个结论 我向哈蒙德提议进行一场比赛
To find out I radioed Hammond and suggested a race.
哈蒙德 我建议我们比个赛
Hammond I propose some form of competition
好啊 拉力赛吗
Excellent, is it rallying
不是拉力赛
No, not rallying
你想嘛 这俩车都有拉力血统
Think about it,both of these are rally cars,
初代迷你Cooper和奥迪Quattro
the original Mini Cooper and Audi Quattro
-完美啊 -那都几百年前的事了
Perfect. That was a million years ago
现在是城市小钢炮
These are now urban
所以我提议
pocket rocket, so I propose
我们就比
we have a race
进锡耶纳城吧 第一个抵达Campo的获胜
into the middle of Siena,ok? First one to the Campo wins
-Campo是啥 -Campo就是城中心一个广场
What is the Campo? Campo is like a square in middle of the city,
但不是方形的 是个赛马的地方
except it is not square.It is where they have the horse race
那就是一片草地喽
Well, so it is grass
不是 是鹅卵石 额 这样 最后一个到的
No, it is cobbled. Errrn, anyway listen, right, last one to get there
明天要穿一整天的白色七分裤 怎么样
has to wear white three quarters length trousers all day tomorrow, ok?
三 二 一 走
Three, Two,One, Go.
行了 哈蒙德已然走错方向了
Right, Hammond has gone wrong
也就是说我要找一条鹅卵石的赛马道
So I am looking for a cobbled horse track
位于一个不是广场的广场
in a square that isn't square
如果我输了就得穿白色七分裤
and that if I lose I have to wear white three quarters length trousers
一整天 这都什么啊 -首先
for a day, my life is weird. Right, first things first,
我得把它设定到动力模式
I must put everything in dynamic mode there we are.
于是强化了 唉没有强化
Now that firms up ...Oh no it doesn't firm everything up,
悬挂直接凝固 这明明是震动模式 还是用自动吧
it solidifies the suspension,they should call it bouncematic,back into auto.
但这样就没有那么犀利了 而且还没高尔夫R推背感那么强
And now we've lost the sharpness,also it isn't as accelerative as a Golf R.
我就纳闷了 既然小了
And I don't know how that can be, I mean it is smaller
怎么会不快了呢
why isn't it faster?
迷你太大 奥迪太差
so the Mini was too big the Audi was all wrong
我们俩进城的方向也完全不同
and we'd both entered Siena from completely different directions.
我感觉这应该是往中心走的方向
I think it is right in towards the centre,
我这大圆导航能看天气
looking I am a big sat-nav here,which can take into account the weather
但是却看不到那破campo在哪
what it can't do is find a campo or whatever it is called.
已经说了S1动力模式太蹦而自动模式又太平
We've established then the S1 is bouncy in dynamic mode and bland in auto mode.
但考虑到其25000镑的售价
but 25,000 Pounds
至少可以给个 太贵 的评价
it is at least expensive
而且你买的也不是正经四驱
And it is not like you are paying for four wheel drive,
因为大部分时间都是前驱
because most of the time it is front wheel drive
只在危急时 一半的动力才会输送到后桥
only in dial emergencies is half the power sent to the back.
与此同时 哈蒙德也遇到了他的问题
Meanwhile,Hammond was having some issues,as while.
我真心应该开个小车而不是Mini
What I should have done is bringing some small car rather than a Mini
欧
Oh
不行
I can't do it. Oh
我滴妈呀
Oh,great moses.
不好意思 分神了
Sorry I get slightly distracted
行了
Right,ok.
当然了 锡耶纳是不允许汽车通行的 除了路边的这些
Car are of course banned from Siena,apart from these ones,
在意大利
you can have as many laws
只要不强制执行 你要停多少都可以
as you like in Italy just so long as they are not enforced.
我知道制片人的想法
I can see what the producers were thinking here,
锡耶纳 小车 迷你 明显是电影"偷天换日"
knowing we were around Siena,small car,Mini,Italian Job.
但是我想指出几点 要是电影里用这车
Couple of points there, if the Italian Job would have been done in this,
第一场戏都拍不完
they would end in the first scene,
因为车早就卡在隧道里出不来了
because the car would have been stuck in the tunnel.
太大了
It is big.
十分钟过去了 这已经不像比赛 更像是一场逃亡
Ten minutes in,it become less about a race and more about survival.
不对 我肯定来过这
No, right, I have definitely been there before.
完了我在绕圈
I am going round in circles.
你要是住这的 怎么报地址?
What if you lived there, how would you tell me when it was there.
就是一个棕色高楼旁边的一个棕色高楼
It is a tall brown building opposite to a tall brown building
对面的一个棕色高楼 这哪找去
next to some tall brown buildings, well that is everywhere.
我迷路了
Lost.
这的人看着岁数都挺大了
Some of these people are quite aged,
我估计他们肯定花了一辈子都在找路出去
I suspect that they have been looking for a way out all their lives.
这不是Campo
This isn't the Campo.
这是广场 但不是我要找的那个
It is a square,but it's not the square I am looking for.
不好 死胡同
Oh, dead end.Not good.
拉手刹
Using the hand break.
还真行
Yes, it works
这是正经手刹可不是按钮
and it is a proper hand break, not an electronic button.
有车
Oh cars.
到处都是人 太危险了
People everything, really dangerous.
我穿 借过
squeezing coming through.
完蛋了 我要
This is hopeless, I am gonna...
等会 这不就是个大楼吗 就是这 特征都能对上
hang on,that is a big building,this is it,the signs were all right.
一这不是方形的
One it is not square
二是鹅卵石地面 三 TMD杰里米 克拉克森也在这
Two it is cobbled. Three it has got a Jeremy Bloody Clarkson in it.
他人呢
Where is he?
哈蒙德
Hammond
早啊 我在想明天
Hello. Just thinking tomorrow
我打算穿一条蓝裤子 裤筒一直到地的那种
I am gonna wear blue trousers that go all the way to the ground.
-随你便 -因为你怎么来着 哦对了
Whatever, never mind all that. Because you are...I know
-输了 -行行 无所谓
Lost. Whatever, never mind all that.
-你吃的是肉酱意面吗 -没错
Is that a spaghetti bolognese? Yes, it is
-是的好吃极了 -我也要吃
Yes, it is.Well, I want some. Delicious
但是人家这管这个可不叫spaghetti bolognese
But it is not called spaghetti bolognese here.
-那叫什么 -人家叫
What's it called? It's called
"丫丫阿爸烂大"
Yayam Abalanda
丫丫阿爸烂大
Yayam abalanda
一份丫丫阿爸烂大，谢谢
Please, yayam abalanda
你个混球
Oh, you total plum sack
你太幼稚啦
You childish
要像成年人啊
You are a grown man
由于我们俩都不怎么喜欢这两台车
干脆就把它们扔在Campo
As neither of us had particularly enjoyed our car,
we left them in the Campo
然后步行找宾馆去了
and went off to find a hotel on foot
你知道吗 这东西用了三百年才建好
Do you know it took them 300 years to build that
-关我毛事 -不是 你设想一下
Not interested. No, but if you imagine
一个教堂
starting a cathedral
从1714年开始建 直到今天才完工
in 1714 and then finishing it today
那岂不是每一部分都不一样
it would been all different as it went up
-关我毛事! -玻璃顶...
Not interested. Glass roof...
第二天早上 哈蒙德走出宾馆的时候
The next morning, Hammond emerged from the hotel
看着就像个傻帽
looking ridiculous
但是他所选的车让他不能再傻了
but not as ridiculous as he looked when he got into the car he had chosen
新款雪佛兰克维尔特Stingray
the new Chevrolet Corvette Stingray
你可想清楚了
So let's just get this straight
你打算从这 锡耶纳
You are going to drive from here in Siena
到罗马
to Rome
开这辆雪佛兰克维尔特
in a Chevrolet Corvette while wearing a white
还穿这条白色七分裤
three quarters length trousers.
是的 七分裤
Yes, well the trousers
都怪你 而且这一趟要150英里
is your fault and it is 150 miles
这又是台好车 所以150英里在敞篷的克维尔特里
this is a brilliant car, 150 miles in a Corvette with the roof down
我没问题 非常开心
really does not worry me, I am perfectly happy.
拜拜了您呐
Goodbye.
这才完美 6.2L的美制大V8
Oh, this is perfection. 6.2 litres of American V8 grunt,
除了我的裤子以外 我今天十分满意
apart from the stride, I am a very happy boy today.
不不不 我才更满意 因为我开的是阿尔法罗密欧4C
No, No, No, I am the happy boy today, because I am in an Alfa Romeo 4C.
行驶在通向罗马的阳光大道上
The sun is shining and I am on my way to Rome.
这车从上到下 每一个细节都为了减重而设计
Everything about this car, every single detail,was designed to be light.
举个例子 底盘是碳纤维的
The chassis for example is a carbon fiber tub
就跟F1赛车和迈凯轮P1一样
same as you get on a F1 car or a McLaren P1.
重65公斤 整车也只有900公斤重
It weighs 65 Kg, the whole car only weighs 900 Kg,
这也就意味着这车不需要大排量引擎
and that means it does not need a big engine.
于是镶在驾驶员身后的
Which is why mounted just behind the driver is
是1.7L的涡轮增压发动机 输出237匹的马力
a small 1.7 litre turbo charged engine which develops just 237 bhp.
我知道这听着不多 但对于一根羽毛来说 相信我 足够了
Does not sound like much, but in a feather, trust me it is.
这简直比克维尔特好不只一个档次
This is so much better than the Corvette.
哈蒙德
Hammond
说 你持有枪支吗
Yes? Do you own a gun?
干嘛
Why?
你发现导航后面留出的储物格吗
Have you found the little cabby hole behind the sat-nav screen in there?
这呢 我看见了
Here it is. Yes, I have found it.
那是放你手枪和圣经的地方
That is where you put your pistol and your Bible.
人民军队爱人民 上帝保佑大美帝
Suport the troops.God bless America.
我就知道他肯定会笑话我
I know he is gonna be laughing at me,
看那伯明翰乡巴佬开着一V8跑车
look at that idiot Brummie redneck with his V8 motor,
但是他和我一样清楚这不是什么老美破烂坦克
but he knows as well as I do this is not some crude primitive yank tank,
这是辆现代化的车
this is a modern car.
从头到脚都是全新的
It is all new,
集成老版的唯二部分 一个是出风口
the only 2parts carried forward from the old Corvette are an air vent
另一个是过滤系统 还有敞篷版的顶棚弹簧锁 然后就没了
and the filter system and on the convertible version the roof latch,that's it.
除了那些 这是辆由把人类送上月球上的民族
Otherwise this is an entirely new car from the people
造出来的全新车 这辆车还很快
who put a man on the moon. It's fast too.
V8引擎能够输出高达460匹的马力 极速305km/h
The V8 now delivers a whopping 460 bhp and a top speed of 190 mph.
为了证明哈蒙德什么都不懂
Keen to show Hammond that he knows nothing.
我停在罗马市中心来给他上一课
I pulled over here in the centre of Rome to teach him a lesson.
这就是罗马
So,this is Rome.
没错 我以为到处是古董才对
Yeah. I thought it was all full of old staff.
不不 你像斗兽场啊还有那些台阶什么的
No, No, the Colosseum and those steps
那些都是游客去的在郊区
they are in a sort of suburb where tourists go
这里才是真正的市中心
this is the actual city centre here
这是罗马的中心
This is the centre of Rome.
所以说罗马不是一天建成的
Yes, why it was not built in a day
因为得造这啊 要好久
because they had to do this place, it took forever
你在这开过吗
Have you ever driven around it?
没 所以你也从没在这撞过
No. So you never crashed here then?
都没开过嘛
No, never driven here.
你要不要试试在罗马的中心
Why don't you see if you can do a lap
跑一圈
of the centre of Rome
还不带撞的
without crashing.
我打算试试
I will give it a shot.
-就是 试试啊 -我还真打算
Give it a shot. I will give that a go.
试试
Give it a shot. Yes
座位烫屁股了 太烫了
Seat's hot. It's really hot.
-是吗 -非常烫 不过
Is it? Really hot. I tell you what though
-什么 -这是市中心的是吧
What? This is a city centre, isn't it?
-是啊 -那样的话我们的规则你懂得
Yes. Well in that case you know the rules
升起顶棚
roof up.
哦对 可别让人们看到你那七分裤
Oh yeah, don't want people to see those trousers.
看见没 美国制造
See? American engineering.
这能放几把AK和M16
Couple of AKs down here and M16
省省吧你
Shut up
和共和党的传单
and a vote Republican flyer.
好的 女士们先生们 我们即将见证
Right, ladies and gentlemen,we are now going to see
哈蒙德能否在赛道上飚一圈不带撞的
if Richard Hammond could do a lap of racetrack without crashing
他就要出发了
and here he goes
释放你的马力吧
Unleash that power!
这里稍稍右转所以我把车驶向左侧做好准备
So there is a bit of right hander here I will get it to the left ready.
我觉得大概应该转这么多
I think about that much of steering.
完美切弯 哦这还是个双弯心
Kissing the apex, oh it's a double apex corner this.
感觉了好极了
This is nice.
就像变成詹姆斯梅一样 很惬意
It is like being James May,it is restful.
我真不知道我们平时为啥嘲笑他
I don't know why we mock him for it.
在确保给哈蒙德留下足够的空间施展
我开着阿尔法也出发了
Making sure that I'd given Hammond plenty of room, I set off in the Alfa.
因为4C几乎是正方形的
Because the 4C is virtually square,
长宽差不多 所以抓地力简直爆表
it is as wide as it's long,the grip is just incredible.
而且还没有多余的重量让你偏离弯心
And because there is not weight dragging you out of shape,
所以你过弯的速度不可思议
you can go around corners at speeds that just boggle the mind.
下面是双急弯
And now the chicane.
这车的驾乘感受简直无敌了
The feel from this car is sublime.
我彻底爱上她了
I am totally and utterly in love with this car.
看 那是理查德哈蒙德
Oh hello, there is Richard Hammond.
跪舔我大阿尔法吧
Yes, eat my Alfa.
我会忽略刚才发生的一切 我不会被影响
I am gonna ignore that. I am not gonna get drawn into anything.
我在我的能力范围内驾驶
I am driving within my limits.
有一本汽车杂志 我就不点名道姓了
One of the motoring magazine,which shall remain nameless,save it,
姓Au名tocar的 他们说4C漂不起来
that it begins with an "Au" and ends in "tocar"they say that you can't slide a 4C.
那你管刚才那叫啥
So what was that?
天呐 终点线就在前方
Oh God, there is the line.
我要成功了
I am gonna do it.
他在那 哈蒙德马上要完成他的单圈了
There he is, Richard Hammond has nearly completed his lap.
让我们减速 见证这个时刻
Let's slow down and savor the moment.
你看着点
Oh, yes..Watch this
我撞线了
and across the line!
干得好兄弟 说真的 我真的很佩服
Well done mate, that is, I am impressed actually
在那么大的马力的情况下你还能成功
because that is a lot of horsepower in that thing and you've done it.
哈蒙德现在嫌"龟速船长开法"太无聊
Hammond now bored of driving like
于是决定彻底释放他那V8的威力
Captain Slow decided he was ready to finally unleash his V8.
发--射
And launch!
你知道什么更酷炫吗
You know something super cute？
他只有每吨256匹的马力
He has got what 256 bhp per ton,
我每吨有302匹所以我的更好 就这么简单
I've got 302 and that is better. Fact.
他最高时速是257km/h 我最高306
He has a top speed of 160, I have a top speed of 190.
闪开 小虫子 你这小破车
Out of my way, insect, you are a tiny little car.
不要啊
Come on! No!
这预示着一场天人之战的序幕
This heralded the start of a David Goliah Battle not seen,
在迷你与福特猎鹰的BBTC之战后
就再没见过这样的了
since Minis used to take on Ford Falcons in the BTCC.
哈蒙德和他的克维尔特 在摧毁雨林 屠杀北极熊
Hammond in his Corvette,he is destroying the forrest,he is killing polar bears
而且他还穿着白色七分裤 这些都是犯罪
and he is wearing white three quarters length trousers in this is a bad crime.
真是辆好车
This is a bloody good car.
没错人家是体型巨大 但是身手矫捷啊
Yes, it is enormous, but my God it can look after itself.
这太神奇了 这条赛道的第一段基本就是克维尔特的领域
It's amazing, the first part of this track is very much Corvette territory,
但是现在这第二部分 就是阿尔法的天下了
but the second part where I am now,this is Alfa town.
他不可能走内线的
He is never going to go the inside.
不会吧
No way.
加油啊 小阿尔法
Come on, little Alfa.
注意看 超过去了
And look,it is coming through.
-去他的 -受着吧
Damn it. Have that.
不好 又回到直道了
No I'm back on the straight again.
天吖 它确实有几分能耐
God it got some grounds.
极速驶过直道
masive speed though the straight.
巨无霸汉堡确实比意式烤面包在直道快
The Big Mac is faster on the straight than the bruschetta.
很多圈过后 哈蒙德明智的认为应当进维修区缓一缓
After many many laps, Hammond sensibly decided we should go into the pits.
再这么下去
We carry on like this,
我们会出事的
we are going to crash.
就你会吧
Well you are.
反正 我有个好点子
Anyway, I have genuinely had an idea.
-什么? -我确实想知道哪辆车更快
What?Right. I would love to find out which of this two is the fastest.
最好的办法是让科学说话
And the best way to do that is to use science,
也就是派出试替哥
and the best way to do that is to use the Stig.
让试替哥尽全力分别开一圈
We put the Stig in each of the two cars,one hot lap,in each car.
用圈速判定出
Then we will have the definitely answer
两台截然不同的座驾 哪台在这里更快
which of this two very different cars is fastest around this track.
所以我得把钥匙交给试替哥
So you are asking me to give this keys of
让它开走我最爱的小车
the nicest little car I've ever driven to the Stig.
-你真的爱上她了-没错
You really have fallen for that. Yes,I have
但你必须那么做
Well you gonna have to hand it out.
说实话 不开玩笑 我确实想知道
Actually, joking apart, I'm quite interesting in that.
因为我知道 在赛道上半段
Cause I would like to know,I know the first half of the track,
考维特比较快
the Corvette is gonna be quick,
下半段 阿尔法比较快
the second half, the Alfa's quick.
因为下半段是阿尔法的地盘啊
Cause the second half is Alfa land.
没错 就这么着 请它来吧
No I agree, let's find him, and make him do that.
不知道它哪去了
I don't know.
不知怎的 我们离开维修区来到赛事控制室的功夫
Somehow between us leaving the pits and getting to race control,
试替哥已经把考维特停到起跑线
Stig have lined up the Corvette on the start line.
-我喜欢这样 -我也是
I like this. I do.
能看到赛道的每个角落吗
Can we get on to see our track.
用这个能看到别人家的卧室吗
Can we see in people's bedrooms with this one.
-可以 -真的? -不行吧 实际上..
Yes Jeremy. Can we. No. Actually.
他在那
There he is.
天 他开的飞快
God he's go very fast.
我真真的想知道谁更快  我也是
I'm genuinely fascinated which of it is the quickest.I am.
挺奇怪的 因为 这比赛是
It is wired though. Cause it is …where we at is…
复古风格和未来趋势的对决
it's the future and the past have come together here for a battle.
我觉得你有点上纲上线啦
I'm not sure if you are not brag it up a bit too much.
我没错 考维特代表了复古风格的延续
It is true. Corvette is sort of last of the past. Yeah.
阿尔法呢 未来的造车理念都会向它靠拢
And the Alfa is, all cars is gonna have to be built like the Alfa.
好的 它驾驶的考维特冲线了
Right so he's finished, he's gonna cross the line in a Corvette.
于是轮到阿尔法了
Which meant it was the Alfa's turn.
承认吧 哈蒙德 它好看多了
Come on Hammond, it looks better than yours.
不 风格不同 它确实也漂亮
No it's different. It's very good-looking.
我承认肯塔基的胖子们把你的车设计的不错
I admit the fat men from Kentucky have done a very good job with your car,
但他们终究只是肯塔基的胖子们
but they are ultimately fat men from Kentucky.
这可是米兰的工程师们设计的
This was designed by engineers from Milan.
唯一的问题是 你那辆小东西确实不错
The only thing is, that's a very nice little object,
不过它才和薄荷糖差不多大 做好也简单
but it could equally be a very nice peppermint
好的 冲线了
Well that was it, crossed the line.
他到终点了 完成了?
Is he crosse the line? He's done?
没错 我们等着看圈速吧
Yes he's done,there we are,so now we wait the times.
阿尔法的圈速
Alfa time?
谢谢你 考维特的圈速
Thank you. Corvette time.
2分
Two
2分 -真的?
Two.Oh really
对啊 你想想
Yeah you see. Now you see
-真的吗 -对啊
Is it? It is.
但你的马力强那么多
So all that extra power.
咦 是啊
Oh yeah.
我们都是2分多
And we were both at 2 minutes 0.
下面这个数字小于5
My number is less than 5.
我也是
So is mine.
2分03秒
2 minutes 3,
1.6秒 太棒了
1.6. Yes!
结果很清楚 我是说
But that's all there is.3.4 I mean that is.
2分3秒4 和 2分1秒6
2:03:4 and 2:01:6
只快了1.8秒
It's 1.8 faster.
不赖啊 我觉得这太棒了
It's not bad is it. I think that is amazing.
总之我们得驾驶这两辆
Anyway we must know drive these cars
开进有着众多古迹的罗马郊区了
into the suburb of Rome with the old stuff in it.
那才是我在电视里经常见的
That's the stuff I've seen on the tele.
你知道 游客去的地方
Yes,you know the stuff tourist. The tourist.
那么我们进城住一晚
So we drive them in there and stay the night.
我是不还得穿...没错
Have I got to still wear the …Yes
那晚我非常开心
That night I was felling very happy
因为带着猩猩进了罗马城
that I put the orangutan in its place,
但当我驶入古迹众多的罗马的时候
but as I arrived in the suburb of Rome with the old buildings and stuff
我迫切的想和他换车
I would have changed places with him in a heartbeat.
罗马的每辆车 都是灰色的小掀背
Every single car in Rome is a small grey dented hatchback,
确实如此
it's just what they are.
他们可不是红色的美式敞篷
They are not red American droptop.
你必须承认你选错车了
You must admit you've got the wrong car here.
我完全同意
I can not possibly argue otherwise.
你就不能换条路去酒店吗
Could you take a different route to the hotel?
不 我就是故意和你并排 这样别人就知道咱俩是好基友
No, I'm driving alongside you deliberately so people know we are together.
我是他伙计 哥俩好
I'm his mate, I'm with him.
这辆车在罗马 好比生日蛋糕上的蜡烛 相得益彰
This car sits in Rome like a candle sits on a birthday cake,
而那辆 宛如蛋糕上的一坨翔
the Corvette sits in Rome like a turt sits on a birthday cake.
第二天 哈蒙德坚持要换车
The next day Hammond insisted we change cars,
鉴于在开往阿马尔菲海岸的沿途 路况多样
so as we have to drive to the Amalfi Coast on a variety of roads
我们换上了两辆比较多功能的小车
we switch to two cars that can do a variety of things.
奔驰 A45 AMG 和 大众 Golf R
The Mercedes AMG A-Class and the VW Golf R.
两者都是2升涡轮增压引擎
Both have 2L turbo-charged engines,
都是德制高品质 都是四驱
German-built quality and four wheel drive.
这俩基本是有史以来最强劲的钢炮
These are just about the hottest hot hatches ever made.
哦 好多了 我融入这里了
Oh this feels better,I'm blending,
人在罗马 入乡随俗
I'm in Rome doing as the Romans are doing.
当然没错
Which is a good thing.
我明白你需要换成灰色小掀背
I can see why you needed to switch to a grey hatchback,
可我没什么必要啊
but why did I need to switch?
你不是喜欢加强版高尔夫么
Well you like a fast Golf.
阿尔法挺不错的 她哪去了
The Alfa was fine, where is it?
我把她交给阿尔法的工作人员了
I'm given the Alfa back to the man from Alfa Romeo.
那我不会再见到她了是吗
So I'm never seeing it again?
怎么 你还放不下她了吗
Oh god, are you going to pine for it?
要是以后驾驶她的人对她不好怎么办
What if somebody else drives it that isn't kind to it?
要是谁驾驶的时候 也很享受呢
What if somebody else drives it and it really enj oys it?
不 不准你那么说
No No, stop saying these things.
他们相遇在罗马 他是个很丑的大块头
They met in Rome. He was a big ugly man.
她是辆小巧的阿尔法罗密欧
She was a small slip of a Alfa Romeo.
但排除万难 他们结合 走到了一起
And despite all odds, they got together, and they got on.
终有一天 她离去了 独留猩猩黯然神伤
And then one day she was gone, and the big ape was sad.
人家只想要4C
I like the 4C.
杰里米还在想着前女友的时候
With Jeremy still pining for his Alfa,
我们离开罗马 南下241公里 驶向阿马尔菲海岸
we left Rome for the 150-mile-dirve south to the Amalfi Coast.
这是奔驰的首辆小钢炮
This is Mercedes'first ever hot hatch.
他们看看别人的小掀背 就决定
And they've just look at hot hatches and thought
"好吧 动力要强
"Right,it needs to be powerful,
速度要快 必须稳重 时髦 不吵
and fast, and discreet,and stylish, quietly."
于是他们造出了终极钢炮
And then they just make the ultimate hot hatch.
"瞧 我们造出来了"
"There you go, we've done it."
2升涡轮增压引擎迸发出355匹马力
355 break horsepower form a modiest 2L compacity turbo charged engine.
四驱 7速双离合变速箱
Four wheel drive,seven speed,double clutch gearbox,
零百加速4.3秒 极速限定在270km/h
0-60 4.3 seconds,top speed limited to 168.
"搞定 我们赢了"
"That is it, we have won the game."
但是 奔驰售价将近3.8万英镑
But, the Mercedes cost nearly 38000 pounds,
比这辆Golf贵了7千镑 会快的那么多吗
7000 more than the golf,so is it really that much faster?
3 2 1 出发
3 2 1 Go
没错 你自己看 直接就跑远了
No, you just look at that, that is just romping away.
是啊 这个快得多
Yeah this is faster.
对于2升的小车 297马力确实不少
Well this is 297 break horsepower, that's a lot from a 2L car.
那他们是怎么从你那台里榨出355的?
Where the hell have they got 355 from in yours?
2升的引擎里萃出355匹！
355 break form a 2L!
对于掀背来说 确实快的匪夷所思
For a hatchback, that is ludicrously fast.
有感于去年公路之路的半途夭折
Mind full of premature end to last year's road trip,
我们转而开始温柔地巡航
we settle down into a gentle cruise.
天哪 别让他看到火山
Oh god. Don't let him see the volcano
要不他会花一整天研究那些石头之类的
or we'll end up spending the rest of the day groping rocks or things.
哈蒙德 那是维苏威火山吗
Hammond, is that the Vesuvius over there?
不 不是
No, no it's not.
绝对是
Yes it is.
那就是说我们快到庞培古城了
That means we are very close to Pompeii.
请不要让我浪费一下午时间在那研究破石头
Please don't make me spend the afternoon standing about groping rocks.
你让我开拼装车 我就让你去庞培
You made me driving a kit-kart, I'm making you going to Pompeii.
万幸 庞培古城人有点多
Happily however, Pompeii was a bit touristy.
我俩被认出来了
Hammond I may have caught up a bit here.
这主意真棒
Oh great idea this is.
于是我们的观光计划没戏了
Which meant our sightseeing was impossible.
感谢你观看节目
Thank you for watching it.
"我太爱你啦"
"I love you so much."
"安德鲁 击个掌"
"Andrew give me a hand"
我不叫安德鲁
I'm not Andrew
谢谢你看节目
Thanks for watching the show.
他们以为我叫安德鲁
They think I'm called Andrew.
于是安德鲁和我很快继续开往苏莲托
Which meant that Andrew and I were soon back on our way to Sorrento.
但是 制作人要求我们暂停
However, the producers then made us pull over to
在世上最糟的地点录制预告
do promotional activity at the worst location ever.
为什么不是你读呢
But why didn't you read this?
你咋不读呢
Why didn't you read it?
女士们先生们 受BBC合同附属细则之命
Ladies and gentlemen propelled in front of the camera
我们站在镜头前
by the small print in their contrast.
因为BBC的律师要比我们的律师强
Cause the BBC's lawyers are better than our lawyers,
在这里向你们介绍我们的新D-VD
we are here to tell you about our new D-VD.
我们的全新DVD叫做最...叫啥来着?
Our brand new top gear DVD is called top-What is it called?
我们的全新DVD叫做完美公路之旅2
Our brand new top gear DVD is called The Perfect Road Trip 2.
内容如下 这样是不是太啰嗦了
and here's some of the things with -- that's too much isn't it
如果你们很感兴趣的话
just in case you were wondering
如果你们
just in case you
在今年全新的 DVD
this year for our all new Top Gear DVD
节目中我们洗心革面 重新做人
we've been working hard to put right all the things went wrong
乐队开始演奏了
the band started.the band started.Tell me
乐队 还有大炮
the band is make ohh the cannon
这也是醉了
oh that's got it that's shifted it
真是选的一手好地点啊
best location ever isn't it --superb
欢迎光临 BBC 商城 即将上映
hello BBC shop coming up now
-只是一家商城吗 -啥? -不只是一家吧
Just One shop -- what --Just One shop
你好镜报读者!
hello the Mirror coming up
太阳报汽车版你们好啊!
hello Sun Motors and coming up
你好Bling Box! 虽然我不认识你们 但是
hello Bling Box I have literally no idea who you are but coming up
-尼罗河商城好啊 -是亚马逊
hello Nile coming up now.It's Amazon
iTunes用户你们好 你将看到全新DVD特辑完美公路之旅2
hello iTunes coming up now some exclusive action from brand-new Top Gear DVD
-其中的独家片段 -嘭!
the perfect road trip 2 --bang
我要忍住
I better hold out.
真是碉堡了
It's explosive
有史以来最差的 -哔-嘭
that is the worst ever *** bang
搞完这些公关的破事以后我们开始坐下来聊聊车
with the contractual obligation fulfilled we settled down to talk about cars
P1 是最棒的
P1 it is the best
好吧
yes
我觉得就是的
no it is, I mean it just is
我可不想讨论
look I'm not admitting to anything about it
P1 和 918 到底谁快谁慢
being quicker or slower than 918 but
但是 P1 确实很耀眼很惊艳
yeah that was dazzled I was amazed
前所未有的体验
it feels unlike anything else
考维特Stingray也带来了很大的惊喜 我知道你暗恋这车
big surprise the Corvette Stingray which I know you secretly like
我明明是公开的喜欢这车
no I don't secretly like I publicly like the Corvette
考维特是不错 但是
yeah the Corvette's a good car but
得了吧 又来了
come on then here we go
如果要我在这次旅途选车带走
the car I would take away from this
快乐的住在德文或是瑞吉的乡下小屋的话
我选阿尔法4C
then happily live in a cottage in Devon and Regis is the Alfa 4C
说不定还带她去公园里面踢秋天的落叶玩呢
maybe walk through a Park kicking through autumn leaves with it
我已经无法用言语来形容我对这车的爱了
I can't find the words to discribe how much I like that car
在火山的那一头 4C说不定正在自由的前行
somewhere out there beyond the volcano the 4C is roaming free
在某男人操控下
in the hands of another man
有什么我能帮您的么 先生
May I help you sir?Oh.
我要一份肉酱意面
yes could I have a Ragù please
Ragù到底是个啥玩意 你一直说
well what is a Ragù, you always say that
在英国我们把它叫做Spaghetti Bolognese
Ragù, in England we call it Spaghetti Bolognese
原来你每天都在吃啊
well you've had that everyday
是啊
I know
这就是 原来就是一个东西啊 就像番茄炖肉和那啥
and that is spa... well it's the same it's like tomatos and meat
是啊是啊
yeah yeah yeah yeah
你吃完就知道了
you'd eat is and go this is Spaghetti Bolognese
所以这么多天
so you've been having Spaghetti Bolognese essentially
你每天都在吃肉酱意面
every single day of this trip
我都说了我要 Ragù 然后你觉得这名字太恶心了就没要
I said I've had Ragù you said errr that sounds disgusting
为什么不叫Spaghetti Bolognese 而非要叫Ragù
why don't they call it Spaghetti Bolognese why call it Ragù
因为它就叫Ragù
cause it`s called Ragù
这两个东西是一样的吧  是的
a Ragù is Spaghetti Bologese yes -the same
为啥不叫Spaghetti Bolognese
why don't you say Spaghetti Bologese
因为点Spaghetti Bolognese的话端上来的就是香肠意面
because Spaghetti Bologese is a sausage
-真是可怕啊 -才不
it's horrible -- it isn't horrible
第二天早上
the next morning
我们距离Capri还有一段美如画的 16 公里的海滨公路
we were faced a exquisite 10 mile drive along the coast towards Capri
我都觉得当代的新车
and neither of us could think of a single morden car
没有配得上这条路的
that would capture the moment
所以我们找来了两辆经典阿尔法罗密欧
so we went for these two classic Alfa Romeoes
1962年的Touring Spider以及1963年的Giulia Spider
a 1962 Touring Spider and 1963 Giulia Spider
我认为没有更好的选择了
oh I don't think we could have done any better
在恰当的时刻 正确的地点 开合适的车
absolute proof that the right car in the right place
简直不要太爽
at the right moment can add up to perfection
在这段路上 我们本可以驾驶任何一辆之前的车
this stretch of road we could driven it up and down in any morden cars we've driven
但我们想要这种特别感 我们找到了
we wanted something special and boy we have got it
阿尔法
Alfas
阿尔法罗密欧4C的起源可以追溯到这款车
the Alfa Romeo 4C could trace it's root back to this car
Giulia Spider
the Giulia Spider
这正是一切汽车梦幻之旅的基石
this is the dream on which all motoring dreams were built
我知道你看的是
伯明翰小伙子开着一辆借来的意大利车
I know what you all seeing is a short Brummie in a borrowed Italian car
但是在我心中这完全不一样
but the image in my mind is completely different
我就是Clark Gable
Clark Gable
与之后提及人名均为老电影明星
连杰里米坐进那车以后都精神多了
even Jeremy is pulling that off in that car
我就像是Edward Fox和Sophia Loren
in my mind I'm Edward Fox,Sophia Loren
我就是Grace Kelly 不 我才不是她呢
I'm Grace Kelly.No I'm not Grace Kelly,
她就是从这样的悬崖上掉下去的
she plummeted to a death off a road very similar to this
这样不是很有意思嘛
it's funny isn't it
你可以开船路过并羡慕这样的风景
you can sail through a beautiful bit of scenery looking at it and admire it
但是开着这种车
or in a car like this
与景色融为一体
you can become part of that scene
我就是这样爱上汽车的
my love of cars was born from imagery like this
蓝天 大海 山路 和一辆软顶阿尔法
a mountain road a soft top Alfa the bule sky the sea
我找不到比此刻更令人高兴的瞬间了
it's hard to think really how I could be happier in a car that I am now
不过我突然意识到差了点什么
then I remembered actually there was something missing
是时候来段 Monro的音乐了
I guess it's time to cue the Monro now
这简直就是全片的高潮啊
this is the perfect bits of the perfect road trip
不久我们抵达了可以开船通往 Capri 的酒店
Soon we arrived the hotel,from where we could sail to Capri.
然后打着网球喝着柠檬水来庆贺这一刻
And celebrate it with a glass of lemonade in the game of tennis.
-我都没看到球 -太刺激了
I didn't even see it.It was exciting.
15比0 我再怎么样也追不上
Fifteen love(zero).I'm never gonna get that way.
打得不错哦  是的  我知道
Well done,well play.Yeah,I know.
漂亮漂亮
cheers,mate. Good game
绝对没有奉承你哦
There's no claw that.No not really
在打完时长28秒的比赛后 我们边喝柠檬水边讨论了起来
After our epic 28 second match.We have our lemonade and argument.
这柠檬水太好喝了
What delicious lemonade I have ever
-我从没喝过这么好的 -太美味了
I never have better than this.It's very
从没喝过那么好喝的
best I have ever taste.
今天下午
And this afternoon,
我将会驾驶
I shall be driving
一辆3.0升的Capri
a 3 litre Capri
在 Capri 岛上开  等等
on the island Capri.Hang on
只有一辆3.0升的啊
There's only one 3 litre.
-我知道 -那为啥不是我开呢
I know.Well,why it's you have it.
-你可以开2.8升的那一辆啊 -你去开2.8的
You can have a 2.8. No you have the 2.8.I would drive
2.8的马力更大
2.8 is more powerful
2.8 的马力更大
The 2.8 is more powerful
而你又喜欢大马力
And you like POWER,etc
我知道 但是 3.0 升的是化油器版本
Yes,I know.But the 3 litres get the carburettors.Yours
-我要3.0的 -你开电喷的去
I want the 3 litre.You could have the fuel injection.
我不要电喷的 我要更经典的化油器的
I don't want fuel injection,I want carbs.It's a classic car.
不 2.8的才更经典
No no,the 2.8 is classic.
-哥们 你的内心是想要一辆2.8的 -才不是呢
You know you want a 2.8,dude. No,I don't.
于是
And so
我们有了一个计划
we hatch a plan.
计划如下
Here is what gonna happen,
我们各开一艘快艇
we're gonna get a couple of speed boats,
比赛前往Capri
and we gonna race to Capri.
谁先到那里
And whoever get there first
-谁开3.0升的  -我能呵呵一下嘛
has the 3 litre.Yeah,can I make a perfect claim
这纯粹是他的点子
this was his idea
因为他知道我不会开船
he thought it,because I can't drive a boat
那都怪你 你事先应该想到的
Well,it's your fault,you should thought of that.
这是你的主意啊 我可没想开船比赛
Well,I...It's your idea,I wouldn't plan a boat race.
-我们俩商量的啊 -不是 是你一个人
We hatch the plan.No we didn't,you hatch the plan.
因为我不会开船
Because I can't drive a boat.
很简单的啦
It's not difficult
不幸的是 对于这个伯明翰人来讲
Unfortunately,for the man from Birmingham
是困难
it was
准备好了嘛
Are you ready?
没呢
No,I'm not.
-为啥 -因为我不会开船
why not? I don't know how to work it
有两个油门用来控制前后 这是双螺旋桨的
You get those 2 throttles,that's forward and backward.It's twin screw
襟翼用来调节船的高度
You got the flap that trim you out
速度起来以后船头会升高
As you go up,the nose of the boat will raise,
放下襟翼使船头降低保持水平
you put the flaps down that bring the nose down get you on the plane
我又不是开飞机为啥会有襟翼呢 飞机才有啊
I'm not on the plane,why am I got the flaps,they are on planes
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
还没呢
No.I'm still not ready.
开船的时候方向是真的要反着打嘛
The steering,is it true that is the oppsite way on the boat,
要往左就向右打
boat,if you want go left steer right
是啊是啊 真是个傻缺
Yes that's true.That's an idiot.
所以就是两个油门 还是反着的
And so there are two throttles that's easily verse
应该表示向前的意思
"For" means forward,I presume
詹姆斯邦德哪有这么多时间来琢磨 开就是了
James Bond doesn't do this when he gets on a speed boat,just go!
准备 3 2 1 出发
Are you ready? In 3 2 1  Go!
好嘞
Yes
这样才像话嘛
god this is what I called motoring now.
-吓尿啊 -马力全开
I'm scard. -Unleash the power!
急死人了
This is nerve wrecking
我要在Capri岛开3.0升的Capri 我不要2.8的
I want to drive that 3 litre capri on Capri.I don't want the 2.8.
不妙 巨浪来袭
Massive wave there,don't like those.
开起来太蛋疼了
Will they...oh,this is terrible.
他在挣扎 太好了他远远落后
Struggling,yes he is far far behind now.
只有一个点那么大
expect frankly,
雷霆骑士1号向傻子一坨问话
This is Thunder rider 1 to Inappropriate stock
你情况如何
How are you doing?
我的船不叫这个名字
That's not the name of my boat.
我转速是23  你的情况如何
I'm doing 23 aside,what about you?
我听不懂你是啥意思
I don't know what you are talking about.
看看转速表啊 你个超级傻缺
Look at the red counter,you blathering idiot.
感觉不好
Oh,I don't like this.Oh my god
胜利属于我 3.0升Capri 是我的
Victiory is mine,the 3 litre is mine.
不过唯一的问题是
The only trouble was,
我好像找错岛了
the islnd that I was racing towards didn't look anything like Capri.
这不是Capri 这边肯定是意大利
Now,Capri it's not that,it is not..that's definitely Italy.
有人把Capri岛偷走了 我找不到了
Somebody has stolen Capri and it's missing,it'gone.
当杰里米在那嚷嚷的时候
While Jeremy was busy shouting.
我觉得Capri岛在那里
I think that is Capri over there.
我也越来越自信了
I was getting more and more confident.
说实话 这一点也不难
I'll be honest,it's not difficult.
把这两个拉杆往前一掰就行了
You just sort of put these things forward,you know.
我还没意识到时 我就已经追上了 比赛重新开始
Before I knew it,I caught up and the race was back on.
Capri岛近在眼前
With Capri now firmly in our sight,
这就变成了直线加速赛了
it was a stright line drug race to the finish.
哦 速度飙起来了
oh It got some speed up now
来啰 直接冲向终点
Here we go,spread to the finish line.
哦耶
Oh yes
接着很奇怪 我的领先优势没了 神马情况
And then weirdly,I began to loose my lead.Oh,what's that?
速度
The speed!
他是开了什么挂
Oh god,how does that happen?
我觉得我的船马力更大一些
I think my boat got more powerful engine.
我忘记告诉哈蒙德终点线是在港口了
Our finish line was the port.A fact which I fogget to tell Hammond.
胜利是属于我的
Victory is mine oh mine
你往哪走
Where are you going?
我往港口里面开啊 你要去哪
I'm going to the port,where are you going?
天哪 为啥完全没标记
Why isn't it signed,for gods sake.
是时候坦白了
With that,it was the time to fess up
哈蒙德 你知道你的船有多少马力吗
Hammond,do you know how many horsepower your boat got?
-不知道 多少? -500
No,how many? 500
你的有多少呢
Wow,how many have you got?
700马力
我了个去
Oh,for gods sake.
你个骗子
Cheating
轮渡 好大只的轮渡
Ferry,massive ferry.
最终哈蒙德在路人的帮助下把船停好了
Eventually,after Hammond got a man to help him park the boat.
往后倒点
Better rervers
我们来到了两辆Capri面前
We were introduced to our Capris.
太美了
They are beautiful -Gorgeous cars
-好顶赞 -是的
This is it,Hammond -yes
梦想成真了
This is the realization of the dream.
其实我很高兴选了这一辆
I'm actually pleased I got this one.
因为这辆2.8的和我有着更多的共鸣
Cause this is the one that resonate more for me
因为我比你年轻
Because I'm younger than you
我就是这样想的
This is what I think of.
完美极了 我们两在Capri岛上开着Capri
It's perfect.The fact is we both have Capris and this is Capri.
我们成功了 这将是最完美的一个下午
We have done that.This is gonna to be the one of the best afternoons ever.
我们做到了
We have done it.
听听这达格南的美妙之音
listen to that,the sweat music of Dagenham
Dagenham为Capri的装配工厂所在地
仅仅过了几百码...
不幸的是我们的完美公路之旅又一次提前结束了
Unfortunately,once again,our perefect road trip has come to a premature end.
是车的问题啊 不是我做的
It's the car does that,I didn't want do that.Stop,sh
杰里米然后和警官讲了几句意大利语 然后我们就呵呵了
Jeremy then spoke to the officer in Italian,which made everthing worse.
相当的呵呵
a lot worse
你个猪队友
You total plum sack!
TopGear字幕组原创听译制作
新浪微博@TopGear字幕组
我们能喝杯茶嘛
Would it be possible to get us a cup of tea?